
<Christian-Scripture>    
<story>Jesus
</story> 
<book name="Luke">         
{1:1} Forasmuch as many have taken in hand to set forth in order a declaration of those things which are most surely believed among us,        
{1:2} Even as they delivered them unto us, which from the beginning were eyewitnesses, and ministers of the word; 
{1:3} It seemed good to me also, having had perfect understanding of all things from the very first, to write unto thee in order, most excellent Theophilus,        
{1:4} That thou mightest know the certainty of those things, wherein thou hast been instructed. 
{1:5} There was in the days of Herod, the king of Judaea, a certain priest named        Zacharias, of the course of Abia: and his wife [was] of the daughters of Aaron, and her name        [was] Elisabeth. 
{1:6} And they were both righteous before God, walking in all the        commandments and ordinances of the Lord blameless. 
{1:7} And they had no child, because that        Elisabeth was barren, and they both were [now] well stricken in years. 
{1:8} And it came to        pass, that while he executed the priest’s office before God in the order of his course,        
{1:9} According to the custom of the priest’s office, his lot was to burn incense when he        went into the temple of the Lord. 
{1:10} And the whole multitude of the people were praying        without at the time of incense. 
{1:11} And there appeared unto him an angel of the Lord        standing on the right side of the altar of incense. 
{1:12} And when Zacharias saw [him,] he        was troubled, and fear fell upon him. 
{1:13} But the angel said unto him, Fear not,        Zacharias: for thy prayer is heard; and thy wife Elisabeth shall bear thee a son, and thou        shalt call his name John. 
{1:14} And thou shalt have joy and gladness; and many shall        rejoice at his birth. 
{1:15} For he shall be great in the sight of the Lord, and shall drink        neither wine nor strong drink; and he shall be filled with the Holy Ghost, even from his        mother’s womb. 
{1:16} And many of the children of Israel shall he turn to the Lord their        God. 
{1:17} And he shall go before him in the spirit and power of Elias, to turn the hearts        of the fathers to the children, and the disobedient to the wisdom of the just; to make ready        a people prepared for the Lord. 
{1:18} And Zacharias said unto the angel, Whereby shall I        know this? for I am an old man, and my wife well stricken in years. 
{1:19} And the angel        answering said unto him, I am Gabriel, that stand in the presence of God; and am sent to        speak unto thee, and to shew thee these glad tidings. 
{1:20} And, behold, thou shalt be        dumb, and not able to speak, until the day that these things shall be performed, because        thou believest not my words, which shall be fulfilled in their season. 
{1:21} And the people        waited for Zacharias, and marvelled that he tarried so long in the temple. 
{1:22} And when        he came out, he could not speak unto them: and they perceived that he had seen a vision in        the temple: for he beckoned unto them, and remained speechless. 
{1:23} And it came to pass,        that, as soon as the days of his ministration were accomplished, he departed to his own        house. 
{1:24} And after those days his wife Elisabeth conceived, and hid herself five        months, saying, 
{1:25} Thus hath the Lord dealt with me in the days wherein he looked on        [me,] to take away my reproach among men. 
{1:26} And in the sixth month the angel Gabriel        was sent from God unto a city of Galilee, named Nazareth, 
{1:27} To a virgin espoused to a        man whose name was Joseph, of the house of David; and the virgin’s name [was] Mary. 
{1:28}        And the angel came in unto her, and said, Hail, [thou that art] highly favoured, the Lord        [is] with thee: blessed [art] thou among women. 
{1:29} And when she saw [him,] she was        troubled at his saying, and cast in her mind what manner of salutation this should be.        
{1:30} And the angel said unto her, Fear not, Mary: for thou hast found favour with God.        
{1:31} And, behold, thou shalt conceive in thy womb, and bring forth a son, and shalt call        his name JESUS. 
{1:32} He shall be great, and shall be called the Son of the Highest: and        the Lord God shall give unto him the throne of his father David: 
{1:33} And he shall reign        over the house of Jacob for ever; and of his kingdom there shall be no end. 
{1:34} Then said        Mary unto the angel, How shall this be, seeing I know not a man? 
{1:35} And the angel        answered and said unto her, The Holy Ghost shall come upon thee, and the power of the        Highest shall overshadow thee: therefore also that holy thing which shall be born of thee        shall be called the Son of God. 
{1:36} And, behold, thy cousin Elisabeth, she hath also        conceived a son in her old age: and this is the sixth month with her, who was called barren.        
{1:37} For with God nothing shall be impossible. 
{1:38} And Mary said, Behold the handmaid        of the Lord; be it unto me according to thy word. And the angel departed from her. 
{1:39}        And Mary arose in those days, and went into the hill country with haste, into a city of        Juda; 
{1:40} And entered into the house of Zacharias, and saluted Elisabeth. 
{1:41} And it        came to pass, that, when Elisabeth heard the salutation of Mary, the babe leaped in her        womb; and Elisabeth was filled with the Holy Ghost: 
{1:42} And she spake out with a loud        voice, and said, Blessed [art] thou among women, and blessed [is] the fruit of thy womb.        
{1:43} And whence [is] this to me, that the mother of my Lord should come to me? 
{1:44} For,        lo, as soon as the voice of thy salutation sounded in mine ears, the babe leaped in my womb        for joy. 
{1:45} And blessed [is] she that believed: for there shall be a performance of        those things which were told her from the Lord. 
{1:46} And Mary said, My soul doth magnify        the Lord, 
{1:47} And my spirit hath rejoiced in God my Saviour. 
{1:48} For he hath regarded        the low estate of his handmaiden: for, behold, from henceforth all generations shall call me        blessed. 
{1:49} For he that is mighty hath done to me great things; and holy [is] his name.        
{1:50} And his mercy [is] on them that fear him from generation to generation. 
{1:51} He        hath shewed strength with his arm; he hath scattered the proud in the imagination of their        hearts. 
{1:52} He hath put down the mighty from [their] seats, and exalted them of low        degree. 
{1:53} He hath filled the hungry with good things; and the rich he hath sent empty        away. 
{1:54} He hath holpen his servant Israel, in remembrance of [his] mercy; 
{1:55} As he        spake to our fathers, to Abraham, and to his seed for ever. 
{1:56} And Mary abode with her        about three months, and returned to her own house. 
{1:57} Now Elisabeth’s full time came        that she should be delivered; and she brought forth a son. 
{1:58} And her neighbours and her        cousins heard how the Lord had shewed great mercy upon her; and they rejoiced with her.        
{1:59} And it came to pass, that on the eighth day they came to circumcise the child; and        they called him Zacharias, after the name of his father. 
{1:60} And his mother answered and        said, Not [so;] but he shall be called John. 
{1:61} And they said unto her, There is none of        thy kindred that is called by this name. 
{1:62} And they made signs to his father, how he        would have him called. 
{1:63} And he asked for a writing table, and wrote, saying, His name        is John. And they marvelled all. 
{1:64} And his mouth was opened immediately, and his tongue        [loosed,] and he spake, and praised God. 
{1:65} And fear came on all that dwelt round about        them: and all these sayings were noised abroad throughout all the hill country of Judaea.        
{1:66} And all they that heard [them] laid [them] up in their hearts, saying, What manner of        child shall this be! And the hand of the Lord was with him. 
{1:67} And his father Zacharias        was filled with the Holy Ghost, and prophesied, saying, 
{1:68} Blessed [be] the Lord God of        Israel; for he hath visited and redeemed his people, 
{1:69} And hath raised up an horn of        salvation for us in the house of his servant David; 
{1:70} As he spake by the mouth of his        holy prophets, which have been since the world began: 
{1:71} That we should be saved from        our enemies, and from the hand of all that hate us; 
{1:72} To perform the mercy [promised]        to our fathers, and to remember his holy covenant; 
{1:73} The oath which he sware to our        father Abraham, 
{1:74} That he would grant unto us, that we being delivered out of the hand        of our enemies might serve him without fear, 
{1:75} In holiness and righteousness before        him, all the days of our life. 
{1:76} And thou, child, shalt be called the prophet of the        Highest: for thou shalt go before the face of the Lord to prepare his ways; 
{1:77} To give        knowledge of salvation unto his people by the remission of their sins, 
{1:78} Through the        tender mercy of our God; whereby the dayspring from on high hath visited us, 
{1:79} To give        light to them that sit in darkness and [in] the shadow of death, to guide our feet into the        way of peace. 
{1:80} And the child grew, and waxed strong in spirit, and was in the deserts        till the day of his shewing unto Israel.     
</book>    
<book name="Luke"> 
{2:1} And it came        to pass in those days, that there went out a decree from Caesar Augustus, that all the world        should be taxed. 
{2:2} ([And] this taxing was first made when Cyrenius was governor of        Syria.) 
{2:3} And all went to be taxed, every one into his own city. 
{2:4} And Joseph also        went up from Galilee, out of the city of Nazareth, into Judaea, unto the city of David,        which is called Bethlehem; (because he was of the house and lineage of David:) 
{2:5} To be        taxed with Mary his espoused wife, being great with child. 
{2:6} And so it was, that, while        they were there, the days were accomplished that she should be delivered. 
{2:7} And she        brought forth her firstborn son, and wrapped him in swaddling clothes, and laid him in a        manger; because there was no room for them in the inn. 
{2:8} And there were in the same        country shepherds abiding in the field, keeping watch over their flock by night. 
{2:9} And,        lo, the angel of the Lord came upon them, and the glory of the Lord shone round about them:        and they were sore afraid. 
{2:10} And the angel said unto them, Fear not: for, behold, I        bring you good tidings of great joy, which shall be to all people. 
{2:11} For unto you is        born this day in the city of David a Saviour, which is Christ the Lord. 
{2:12} And this        [shall be] a sign unto you; Ye shall find the babe wrapped in swaddling clothes, lying in a        manger. 
{2:13} And suddenly there was with the angel a multitude of the heavenly host        praising God, and saying, 
{2:14} Glory to God in the highest, and on earth peace, good will        toward men. 
{2:15} And it came to pass, as the angels were gone away from them into heaven,        the shepherds said one to another, Let us now go even unto Bethlehem, and see this thing        which is come to pass, which the Lord hath made known unto us. 
{2:16} And they came with        haste, and found Mary, and Joseph, and the babe lying in a manger. 
{2:17} And when they had        seen [it,] they made known abroad the saying which was told them concerning this child.        
{2:18} And all they that heard [it] wondered at those things which were told them by the        shepherds. 
{2:19} But Mary kept all these things, and pondered [them] in her heart. 
{2:20}        And the shepherds returned, glorifying and praising God for all the things that they had        heard and seen, as it was told unto them. 
{2:21} And when eight days were accomplished for        the circumcising of the child, his name was called JESUS, which was so named of the angel        before he was conceived in the womb. 
{2:22} And when the days of her purification according        to the law of Moses were accomplished, they brought him to Jerusalem, to present [him] to        the Lord; 
{2:23} (As it is written in the law of the Lord, Every male that openeth the womb        shall be called holy to the Lord;) 
{2:24} And to offer a sacrifice according to that which        is said in the law of the Lord, A pair of turtledoves, or two young pigeons. 
{2:25} And,        behold, there was a man in Jerusalem, whose name [was] Simeon; and the same man [was] just        and devout, waiting for the consolation of Israel: and the Holy Ghost was upon him. 
{2:26}        And it was revealed unto him by the Holy Ghost, that he should not see death, before he had        seen the Lord’s Christ. 
{2:27} And he came by the Spirit into the temple: and when the        parents brought in the child Jesus, to do for him after the custom of the law, 
{2:28} Then        took he him up in his arms, and blessed God, and said, 
{2:29} Lord, now lettest thou thy        servant depart in peace, according to thy word: 
{2:30} For mine eyes have seen thy        salvation, 
{2:31} Which thou hast prepared before the face of all people; 
{2:32} A light to        lighten the Gentiles, and the glory of thy people Israel. 
{2:33} And Joseph and his mother        marvelled at those things which were spoken of him. 
{2:34} And Simeon blessed them, and said        unto Mary his mother, Behold, this [child] is set for the fall and rising again of many in        Israel; and for a sign which shall be spoken against; 
{2:35} (Yea, a sword shall pierce        through thy own soul also,) that the thoughts of many hearts may be revealed. 
{2:36} And        there was one Anna, a prophetess, the daughter of Phanuel, of the tribe of Aser: she was of        a great age, and had lived with an husband seven years from her virginity; 
{2:37} And she        [was] a widow of about fourscore and four years, which departed not from the temple, but        served [God] with fastings and prayers night and day. 
{2:38} And she coming in that instant        gave thanks likewise unto the Lord, and spake of him to all them that looked for redemption        in Jerusalem. 
{2:39} And when they had performed all things according to the law of the        Lord, they returned into Galilee, to their own city Nazareth. 
{2:40} And the child grew, and        waxed strong in spirit, filled with wisdom: and the grace of God was upon him. 
{2:41} Now        his parents went to Jerusalem every year at the feast of the passover. 
{2:42} And when he        was twelve years old, they went up to Jerusalem after the custom of the feast. 
{2:43} And        when they had fulfilled the days, as they returned, the child Jesus tarried behind in        Jerusalem; and Joseph and his mother knew not [of it. ]
{2:44} But they, supposing him to        have been in the company, went a day’s journey; and they sought him among [their] kinsfolk        and acquaintance. 
{2:45} And when they found him not, they turned back again to Jerusalem,        seeking him. 
{2:46} And it came to pass, that after three days they found him in the temple,        sitting in the midst of the doctors, both hearing them, and asking them questions. 
{2:47}        And all that heard him were astonished at his understanding and answers. 
{2:48} And when        they saw him, they were amazed: and his mother said unto him, Son, why hast thou thus dealt        with us? behold, thy father and I have sought thee sorrowing. 
{2:49} And he said unto them,        How is it that ye sought me? wist ye not that I must be about my Father’s business? 
{2:50}        And they understood not the saying which he spake unto them. 
{2:51} And he went down with        them, and came to Nazareth, and was subject unto them: but his mother kept all these sayings        in her heart. 
{2:52} And Jesus increased in wisdom and stature, and in favour with God and        man.     
</book>      
<book name = "John">        
{2:1} And the third day there was a marriage in Cana of        Galilee; and the mother of Jesus was there: 
{2:2} And both        Jesus was called, and his disciples, to the marriage. 
{2:3}        And when they wanted wine, the mother of Jesus saith unto        him, They have no wine. 
{2:4} Jesus saith unto her,        Woman, what have I to do with thee? mine hour is not yet        come. 
{2:5} His mother saith unto the servants, Whatsoever        he saith unto you, do [it. ]
{2:6} And there were set there six        waterpots of stone, after the manner of the purifying of the        Jews, containing two or three firkins apiece. 
{2:7} Jesus        saith unto them, Fill the waterpots with water. And they        filled them up to the brim. 
{2:8} And he saith unto them,        Draw out now, and bear unto the governor of the feast. And        they bare [it. ]
{2:9} When the ruler of the feast had tasted        the water that was made wine, and knew not whence it was:        (but the servants which drew the water knew;) the governor        of the feast called the bridegroom, 
{2:10} And saith unto        him, Every man at the beginning doth set forth good wine;        and when men have well drunk, then that which is worse:        [but] thou hast kept the good wine until now. 
{2:11} This        beginning of miracles did Jesus in Cana of Galilee, and        manifested forth his glory; and his disciples believed on him.    
</book>    
<book name = "Matthew">        
{3:13} Then cometh Jesus from Galilee to Jordan unto        John, to be baptized of him. 
{3:14} But John forbad him,        saying, I have need to be baptized of thee, and comest thou        to me? 
{3:15} And Jesus answering said unto him, Suffer [it        to be so] now: for thus it becometh us to fulfil all        righteousness. Then he suffered him. 
{3:16} And Jesus,        when he was baptized, went up straightway out of the        water: and, lo, the heavens were opened unto him, and he        saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove, and lighting        upon him: 
{3:17} And lo a voice from heaven, saying, This        is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.     
</book>    
<book name = "Luke">        
{8:22} Now it came to pass on a certain day, that he went        into a ship with his disciples: and he said unto them, Let us        go over unto the other side of the lake. And they launched        forth. 
{8:23} But as they sailed he fell asleep: and there        came down a storm of wind on the lake; and they were        filled [with water,] and were in jeopardy. 
{8:24} And they        came to him, and awoke him, saying, Master, master, we        perish. Then he arose, and rebuked the wind and the raging        of the water: and they ceased, and there was a calm. 
{8:25}        And he said unto them, Where is your faith? And they being        afraid wondered, saying one to another, What manner of        man is this! for he commandeth even the winds and water,        and they obey him.    
</book> 
<book name = "John">        
{19:1} Then Pilate therefore took Jesus, and scourged        [him. ]
{19:2} And the soldiers platted a crown of thorns,        and put [it] on his head, and they put on him a purple robe,        
{19:3} And said, Hail, King of the Jews! and they smote        him with their hands. 
{19:4} Pilate therefore went forth        again, and saith unto them, Behold, I bring him forth to you,        that ye may know that I find no fault in him. 
{19:5} Then        came Jesus forth, wearing the crown of thorns, and the        purple robe. And [Pilate] saith unto them, Behold the man!        
{19:6} When the chief priests therefore and officers saw        him, they cried out, saying, Crucify [him,] crucify [him.]        Pilate saith unto them, Take ye him, and crucify [him:] for I        find no fault in him. 
{19:7} The Jews answered him, We        have a law, and by our law he ought to die, because he        made himself the Son of God.        
{19:8} When Pilate therefore heard that saying, he was        the more afraid; 
{19:9} And went again into the judgment        hall, and saith unto Jesus, Whence art thou? But Jesus gave        him no answer. 
{19:10} Then saith Pilate unto him,        Speakest thou not unto me? knowest thou not that I have        power to crucify thee, and have power to release thee?        
{19:11} Jesus answered, Thou couldest have no power [at        all] against me, except it were given thee from above:        therefore he that delivered me unto thee hath the greater sin.        
{19:12} And from thenceforth Pilate sought to release him:        but the Jews cried out, saying, If thou let this man go, thou        art not Caesar’s friend: whosoever maketh himself a king        speaketh against Caesar.        
{19:13} When Pilate therefore heard that saying, he        brought Jesus forth, and sat down in the judgment seat in a        place that is called the Pavement, but in the Hebrew,        Gabbatha. 
{19:14} And it was the preparation of the        passover, and about the sixth hour: and he saith unto the        Jews, Behold your King! 
{19:15} But they cried out, Away        with [him,] away with [him,] crucify him. Pilate saith unto        them, Shall I crucify your King? The chief priests answered,        We have no king but Caesar. 
{19:16} Then delivered he        him therefore unto them to be crucified. And they took        Jesus, and led [him] away. 
{19:17} And he bearing his        cross went forth into a place called [the place] of a skull,        which is called in the Hebrew Golgotha: 
{19:18} Where        they crucified him, and two others with him, on either side        one, and Jesus in the midst.        
{19:19} And Pilate wrote a title, and put [it] on the cross.        And the writing was, JESUS OF NAZARETH THE KING        OF THE JEWS. 
{19:20} This title then read many of the        Jews: for the place where Jesus was crucified was nigh to        the city: and it was written in Hebrew, [and] Greek, [and]        Latin. 
{19:21} Then said the chief priests of the Jews to        Pilate, Write not, The King of the Jews; but that he said, I        am King of the Jews. 
{19:22} Pilate answered, What I have        written I have written.        
{19:23} Then the soldiers, when they had crucified Jesus,        took his garments, and made four parts, to every soldier a        part; and also [his] coat: now the coat was without seam,        woven from the top throughout. 
{19:24} They said        therefore among themselves, Let us not rend it, but cast lots        for it, whose it shall be: that the scripture might be fulfilled,        which saith, They parted my raiment among them, and for        my vesture they did cast lots. These things therefore the        soldiers did.        
{19:25} Now there stood by the cross of Jesus his mother,        and his mother’s sister, Mary the [wife] of Cleophas, and        Mary Magdalene. 
{19:26} When Jesus therefore saw his        mother, and the disciple standing by, whom he loved, he        saith unto his mother, Woman, behold thy son! 
{19:27}        Then saith he to the disciple, Behold thy mother! And from        that hour that disciple took her unto his own [home.        ]
{19:28} After this, Jesus knowing that all things were        now accomplished, that the scripture might be fulfilled,        saith, I thirst. 
{19:29} Now there was set a vessel full of        vinegar: and they filled a spunge with vinegar, and put [it]        upon hyssop, and put [it] to his mouth. 
{19:30} When Jesus        therefore had received the vinegar, he said, It is finished:        and he bowed his head, and gave up the ghost. 
{19:31} The        Jews therefore, because it was the preparation, that the        bodies should not remain upon the cross on the sabbath day,        (for that sabbath day was an high day,) besought Pilate that        their legs might be broken, and [that] they might be taken        away. 
{19:32} Then came the soldiers, and brake the legs of        the first, and of the other which was crucified with him.        
{19:33} But when they came to Jesus, and saw that he was        dead already, they brake not his legs: 
{19:34} But one of        the soldiers with a spear pierced his side, and forthwith        came there out blood and water. 
{19:35} And he that saw        [it] bare record, and his record is true: and he knoweth that        he saith true, that ye might believe. 
{19:36} For these things        were done, that the scripture should be fulfilled, A bone of        him shall not be broken. 
{19:37} And again another        scripture saith, They shall look on him whom they pierced.        
{19:38} And after this Joseph of Arimathaea, being a        disciple of Jesus, but secretly for fear of the Jews, besought        Pilate that he might take away the body of Jesus: and Pilate        gave [him] leave. He came therefore, and took the body of        Jesus. 
{19:39} And there came also Nicodemus, which at        the first came to Jesus by night, and brought a mixture of        myrrh and aloes, about an hundred pound [weight. ]
{19:40}        Then took they the body of Jesus, and wound it in linen        clothes with the spices, as the manner of the Jews is to bury.        
{19:41} Now in the place where he was crucified there was        a garden; and in the garden a new sepulchre, wherein was        never man yet laid. 
{19:42} There laid they Jesus therefore        because of the Jews’ preparation [day;] for the sepulchre        was nigh at hand.    
</book>     
<book name = "Luke">        
{23:26} And as they led him away, they laid hold upon one        Simon, a Cyrenian, coming out of the country, and on him        they laid the cross, that he might bear [it] after Jesus.        
{23:27} And there followed him a great company of        people, and of women, which also bewailed and lamented        him. 
{23:28} But Jesus turning unto them said, Daughters        of Jerusalem, weep not for me, but weep for yourselves, and        for your children. 
{23:29} For, behold, the days are coming,        in the which they shall say, Blessed [are] the barren, and the        wombs that never bare, and the paps which never gave suck.        
{23:30} Then shall they begin to say to the mountains, Fall        on us; and to the hills, Cover us. 
{23:31} For if they do        these things in a green tree, what shall be done in the dry?        
{23:32} And there were also two others, malefactors, led        with him to be put to death. 
{23:33} And when they were        come to the place, which is called Calvary, there they        crucified him, and the malefactors, one on the right hand,        and the other on the left.        
{23:34} Then said Jesus, Father, forgive them; for they        know not what they do. And they parted his raiment, and        cast lots. 
{23:35} And the people stood beholding. And the        rulers also with them derided [him,] saying, He saved        others; let him save himself, if he be Christ, the chosen of        God. 
{23:36} And the soldiers also mocked him, coming to        him, and offering him vinegar, 
{23:37} And saying, If thou        be the king of the Jews, save thyself. 
{23:38} And a        superscription also was written over him in letters of Greek,        and Latin, and Hebrew, THIS IS THE KING OF THE        JEWS.        
{23:39} And one of the malefactors which were hanged        railed on him, saying, If thou be Christ, save thyself and us.        
{23:40} But the other answering rebuked him, saying, Dost        not thou fear God, seeing thou art in the same        condemnation? 
{23:41} And we indeed justly; for we        receive the due reward of our deeds: but this man hath done        nothing amiss. 
{23:42} And he said unto Jesus, Lord,        remember me when thou comest into thy kingdom. 
{23:43}        And Jesus said unto him, Verily I say unto thee, To day        shalt thou be with me in paradise.     
</book>  
<book name = "John">        
{14:6} Jesus saith        unto him, I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man        cometh unto the Father, but by me. 
{14:7} If ye had known        me, ye should have known my Father also: and from        henceforth ye know him, and have seen him. 
{14:8} Philip        saith unto him, Lord, shew us the Father, and it sufficeth us.        
{14:9} Jesus saith unto him, Have I been so long time with        you, and yet hast thou not known me, Philip? he that hath        seen me hath seen the Father; and how sayest thou [then,]        Shew us the Father? 
{14:10} Believest thou not that I am in        the Father, and the Father in me? the words that I speak        unto you I speak not of myself: but the Father that dwelleth        in me, he doeth the works. 
{14:11} Believe me that I [am]        in the Father, and the Father in me: or else believe me for        the very works’ sake.     
</book>     
<book name = "Philippians">        
{2:5} Let this mind be in you, which was also in Christ        Jesus: 
{2:6} Who, being in the form of God, thought it not        robbery to be equal with God: 
{2:7} But made himself of no        reputation, and took upon him the form of a servant, and        was made in the likeness of men: 
{2:8} And being found in        fashion as a man, he humbled himself, and became obedient        unto death, even the death of the cross.     
</book>      
<book name = "Colossians">        
{1:15} Who is the image of the invisible God, the        firstborn of every creature: 
{1:16} For by him were all        things created, that are in heaven, and that are in earth,        visible and invisible, whether [they be] thrones, or        dominions, or principalities, or powers: all things were        created by him, and for him: 
{1:17} And he is before all        things, and by him all things consist. 
{1:18} And he is the        head of the body, the church: who is the beginning, the        firstborn from the dead; that in all [things] he might have        the preeminence. 
{1:19} For it pleased [the Father] that in        him should all fulness dwell; 
{1:20} And, having made        peace through the blood of his cross, by him to reconcile all        things unto himself; by him, [I say,] whether [they be]        things in earth, or things in heaven.     
</book>    
<book name = "Luke">        
{22:66} And as soon as it was day, the elders of the        people and the chief priests and the scribes came together,        and led him into their council, saying, 
{22:67} Art thou the        Christ? tell us. And he said unto them, If I tell you, ye will        not believe: 
{22:68} And if I also ask [you,] ye will not        answer me, nor let [me] go. 
{22:69} Hereafter shall the Son        of man sit on the right hand of the power of God. 
{22:70}        Then said they all, Art thou then the Son of God? And he        said unto them, Ye say that I am. 
{22:71} And they said,        What need we any further witness? for we ourselves have        heard of his own mouth.       
</book>            


<story>Parables
</story>      
<book name = "Matthew">        
{13:10} And the        disciples came, and said unto him, Why speakest thou unto        them in parables? 
{13:11} He answered and said unto them,        Because it is given unto you to know the mysteries of the        kingdom of heaven, but to them it is not given. 
{13:12} For        whosoever hath, to him shall be given, and he shall have        more abundance: but whosoever hath not, from him shall be        taken away even that he hath. 
{13:13} Therefore speak I to        them in parables: because they seeing see not; and hearing        they hear not, neither do they understand. 
{13:14} And in        them is fulfilled the prophecy of Esaias, which saith, By        hearing ye shall hear, and shall not understand; and seeing        ye shall see, and shall not perceive: 
{13:15} For this        people’s heart is waxed gross, and [their] ears are dull of        hearing, and their eyes they have closed; lest at any time        they should see with [their] eyes, and hear with [their] ears,        and should understand with [their] heart, and should be        converted, and I should heal them. 
{13:16} But blessed        [are] your eyes, for they see: and your ears, for they hear.    
</book>            


<story>Revelations
</story>    
<book name = "Revelations">        
{1:1} The Revelation of Jesus Christ, which God gave        unto him, to shew unto his servants things which must        shortly come to pass; and he sent and signified [it] by his        angel unto his servant John: 
{1:2} Who bare record of the        word of God, and of the testimony of Jesus Christ, and of all        things that he saw. 
{1:3} Blessed [is] he that readeth, and        they that hear the words of this prophecy, and keep those        things which are written therein: for the time [is] at hand.        
{1:4} John to the seven churches which are in Asia: Grace        [be] unto you, and peace, from him which is, and which        was, and which is to come; and from the seven Spirits        which are before his throne; 
{1:5} And from Jesus Christ,        [who is] the faithful witness, [and] the first begotten of the        dead, and the prince of the kings of the earth. Unto him that        loved us, and washed us from our sins in his own blood,        
{1:6} And hath made us kings and priests unto God and his        Father; to him [be] glory and dominion for ever and ever.        Amen. 
{1:7} Behold, he cometh with clouds; and every eye        shall see him, and they [also] which pierced him: and all        kindreds of the earth shall wail because of him. Even so,        Amen. 
{1:8} I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the        ending, saith the Lord, which is, and which was, and which        is to come, the Almighty.        
{1:9} I John, who also am your brother, and companion in        tribulation, and in the kingdom and patience of Jesus Christ,        was in the isle that is called Patmos, for the word of God,        and for the testimony of Jesus Christ. 
{1:10} I was in the        Spirit on the Lord’s day, and heard behind me a great voice,        as of a trumpet, 
{1:11} Saying, I am Alpha and Omega, the        first and the last: and, What thou seest, write in a book, and        send [it] unto the seven churches which are in Asia; unto        Ephesus, and unto Smyrna, and unto Pergamos, and unto        Thyatira, and unto Sardis, and unto Philadelphia, and unto        Laodicea. 
{1:12} And I turned to see the voice that spake        with me. And being turned, I saw seven golden        candlesticks; 
{1:13} And in the midst of the seven        candlesticks [one] like unto the Son of man, clothed with a        garment down to the foot, and girt about the paps with a        golden girdle. 
{1:14} His head and [his] hairs [were] white        like wool, as white as snow; and his eyes [were] as a flame        of fire; 
{1:15} And his feet like unto fine brass, as if they        burned in a furnace; and his voice as the sound of many        waters. 
{1:16} And he had in his right hand seven stars: and        out of his mouth went a sharp twoedged sword: and his        countenance [was] as the sun shineth in his strength. 
{1:17}        And when I saw him, I fell at his feet as dead. And he laid        his right hand upon me, saying unto me, Fear not; I am the        first and the last: 
{1:18} I [am] he that liveth, and was dead;        and, behold, I am alive for evermore, Amen; and have the        keys of hell and of death.        
{1:19} Write the things which thou hast seen, and the        things which are, and the things which shall be hereafter;        
{1:20} The mystery of the seven stars which thou sawest in        my right hand, and the seven golden candlesticks. The        seven stars are the angels of the seven churches: and the        seven candlesticks which thou sawest are the seven        churches.        
{2:1} Unto the angel of the church of Ephesus write;        These things saith he that holdeth the seven stars in his right        hand, who walketh in the midst of the seven golden        candlesticks; 
{2:2} I know thy works, and thy labour, and        thy patience, and how thou canst not bear them which are        evil: and thou hast tried them which say they are apostles,        and are not, and hast found them liars: 
{2:3} And hast        borne, and hast patience, and for my name’s sake hast        laboured, and hast not fainted. 
{2:4} Nevertheless I have        [somewhat] against thee, because thou hast left thy first        love. 
{2:5} Remember therefore from whence thou art        fallen, and repent, and do the first works; or else I will come        unto thee quickly, and will remove thy candlestick out of        his place, except thou repent. 
{2:6} But this thou hast, that        thou hatest the deeds of the Nicolaitanes, which I also hate.        
{2:7} He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith        unto the churches; To him that overcometh will I give to eat        of the tree of life, which is in the midst of the paradise of        God.        
{2:8} And unto the angel of the church in Smyrna write;        These things saith the first and the last, which was dead, and        is alive; 
{2:9} I know thy works, and tribulation, and        poverty, (but thou art rich) and [I know] the blasphemy of        them which say they are Jews, and are not, but [are] the        synagogue of Satan. 
{2:10} Fear none of those things which        thou shalt suffer: behold, the devil shall cast [some] of you        into prison, that ye may be tried; and ye shall have        tribulation ten days: be thou faithful unto death, and I will        give thee a crown of life. 
{2:11} He that hath an ear, let him        hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; He that        overcometh shall not be hurt of the second death.        
{2:12} And to the angel of the church in Pergamos write;        These things saith he which hath the sharp sword with two        edges; 
{2:13} I know thy works, and where thou dwellest,        [even] where Satan’s seat [is:] and thou holdest fast my        name, and hast not denied my faith, even in those days        wherein Antipas [was] my faithful martyr, who was slain        among you, where Satan dwelleth. 
{2:14} But I have a few        things against thee, because thou hast there them that hold        the doctrine of Balaam, who taught Balac to cast a        stumblingblock before the children of Israel, to eat things        sacrificed unto idols, and to commit fornication. 
{2:15} So        hast thou also them that hold the doctrine of the        Nicolaitanes, which thing I hate. 
{2:16} Repent; or else I        will come unto thee quickly, and will fight against them        with the sword of my mouth. 
{2:17} He that hath an ear, let        him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; To him        that overcometh will I give to eat of the hidden manna, and        will give him a white stone, and in the stone a new name        written, which no man knoweth saving he that receiveth [it.        ]
{2:18} And unto the angel of the church in Thyatira        write; These things saith the Son of God, who hath his eyes        like unto a flame of fire, and his feet [are] like fine brass;        
{2:19} I know thy works, and charity, and service, and        faith, and thy patience, and thy works; and the last [to be]        more than the first. 
{2:20} Notwithstanding I have a few        things against thee, because thou sufferest that woman        Jezebel, which calleth herself a prophetess, to teach and to        seduce my servants to commit fornication, and to eat things        sacrificed unto idols. 
{2:21} And I gave her space to repent        of her fornication; and she repented not. 
{2:22} Behold, I        will cast her into a bed, and them that commit adultery with        her into great tribulation, except they repent of their deeds.        
{2:23} And I will kill her children with death; and all the        churches shall know that I am he which searcheth the reins        and hearts: and I will give unto every one of you according        to your works. 
{2:24} But unto you I say, and unto the rest        in Thyatira, as many as have not this doctrine, and which        have not known the depths of Satan, as they speak; I will        put upon you none other burden. 
{2:25} But that which ye        have [already] hold fast till I come. 
{2:26} And he that        overcometh, and keepeth my works unto the end, to him        will I give power over the nations: 
{2:27} And he shall rule        them with a rod of iron; as the vessels of a potter shall they        be broken to shivers: even as I received of my Father.        
{2:28} And I will give him the morning star. 
{2:29} He that        hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the        churches.        
{3:1} And unto the angel of the church in Sardis write;        These things saith he that hath the seven Spirits of God, and        the seven stars; I know thy works, that thou hast a name that        thou livest, and art dead. 
{3:2} Be watchful, and strengthen        the things which remain, that are ready to die: for I have not        found thy works perfect before God. 
{3:3} Remember        therefore how thou hast received and heard, and hold fast,        and repent. If therefore thou shalt not watch, I will come on        thee as a thief, and thou shalt not know what hour I will        come upon thee. 
{3:4} Thou hast a few names even in        Sardis which have not defiled their garments; and they shall        walk with me in white: for they are worthy. 
{3:5} He that        overcometh, the same shall be clothed in white raiment; and        I will not blot out his name out of the book of life, but I will        confess his name before my Father, and before his angels.        
{3:6} He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith        unto the churches.        
{3:7} And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia        write; These things saith he that is holy, he that is true, he        that hath the key of David, he that openeth, and no man        shutteth; and shutteth, and no man openeth; 
{3:8} I know        thy works: behold, I have set before thee an open door, and        no man can shut it: for thou hast a little strength, and hast        kept my word, and hast not denied my name. 
{3:9} Behold,        I will make them of the synagogue of Satan, which say they        are Jews, and are not, but do lie; behold, I will make them to        come and worship before thy feet, and to know that I have        loved thee. 
{3:10} Because thou hast kept the word of my        patience, I also will keep thee from the hour of temptation,        which shall come upon all the world, to try them that dwell        upon the earth. 
{3:11} Behold, I come quickly: hold that        fast which thou hast, that no man take thy crown. 
{3:12}        Him that overcometh will I make a pillar in the temple of        my God, and he shall go no more out: and I will write upon        him the name of my God, and the name of the city of my        God, [which is] new Jerusalem, which cometh down out of        heaven from my God: and [I will write upon him] my new        name. 
{3:13} He that hath an ear, let him hear what the        Spirit saith unto the churches.        
{3:14} And unto the angel of the church of the        Laodiceans write; These things saith the Amen, the faithful        and true witness, the beginning of the creation of God;        
{3:15} I know thy works, that thou art neither cold nor hot:        I would thou wert cold or hot. 
{3:16} So then because thou        art lukewarm, and neither cold nor hot, I will spue thee out        of my mouth. 
{3:17} Because thou sayest, I am rich, and        increased with goods, and have need of nothing; and        knowest not that thou art wretched, and miserable, and poor,        and blind, and naked: 
{3:18} I counsel thee to buy of me        gold tried in the fire, that thou mayest be rich; and white        raiment, that thou mayest be clothed, and [that] the shame        of thy nakedness do not appear; and anoint thine eyes with        eyesalve, that thou mayest see. 
{3:19} As many as I love, I        rebuke and chasten: be zealous therefore, and repent. 
{3:20}        Behold, I stand at the door, and knock: if any man hear my        voice, and open the door, I will come in to him, and will sup        with him, and he with me. 
{3:21} To him that overcometh        will I grant to sit with me in my throne, even as I also        overcame, and am set down with my Father in his throne.        
{3:22} He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith        unto the churches.    
</book>        
<book name = "Revelations">        
{8:1} And when he had opened the seventh seal, there        was silence in heaven about the space of half an hour. 
{8:2}        And I saw the seven angels which stood before God; and to        them were given seven trumpets. 
{8:3} And another angel        came and stood at the altar, having a golden censer; and        there was given unto him much incense, that he should offer        [it] with the prayers of all saints upon the golden altar which        was before the throne. 
{8:4} And the smoke of the incense,        [which came] with the prayers of the saints, ascended up        before God out of the angel’s hand. 
{8:5} And the angel        took the censer, and filled it with fire of the altar, and cast        [it] into the earth: and there were voices, and thunderings,        and lightnings, and an earthquake. 
{8:6} And the seven        angels which had the seven trumpets prepared themselves to        sound.        
{8:7} The first angel sounded, and there followed hail and        fire mingled with blood, and they were cast upon the earth:        and the third part of trees was burnt up, and all green grass        was burnt up. 
{8:8} And the second angel sounded, and as it        were a great mountain burning with fire was cast into the        sea: and the third part of the sea became blood; 
{8:9} And        the third part of the creatures which were in the sea, and had        life, died; and the third part of the ships were destroyed.        
{8:10} And the third angel sounded, and there fell a great        star from heaven, burning as it were a lamp, and it fell upon        the third part of the rivers, and upon the fountains of waters;        
{8:11} And the name of the star is called Wormwood: and        the third part of the waters became wormwood; and many        men died of the waters, because they were made bitter.        
{8:12} And the fourth angel sounded, and the third part of        the sun was smitten, and the third part of the moon, and the        third part of the stars; so as the third part of them was        darkened, and the day shone not for a third part of it, and        the night likewise.        
{8:13} And I beheld, and heard an angel flying through        the midst of heaven, saying with a loud voice, Woe, woe,        woe, to the inhabiters of the earth by reason of the other        voices of the trumpet of the three angels, which are yet to        sound!        
{9:1} And the fifth angel sounded, and I saw a star fall        from heaven unto the earth: and to him was given the key of        the bottomless pit. 
{9:2} And he opened the bottomless pit;        and there arose a smoke out of the pit, as the smoke of a        great furnace; and the sun and the air were darkened by        reason of the smoke of the pit. 
{9:3} And there came out of        the smoke locusts upon the earth: and unto them was given        power, as the scorpions of the earth have power. 
{9:4} And        it was commanded them that they should not hurt the grass        of the earth, neither any green thing, neither any tree; but        only those men which have not the seal of God in their        foreheads. 
{9:5} And to them it was given that they should        not kill them, but that they should be tormented five        months: and their torment [was] as the torment of a        scorpion, when he striketh a man. 
{9:6} And in those days        shall men seek death, and shall not find it; and shall desire        to die, and death shall flee from them. 
{9:7} And the shapes        of the locusts [were] like unto horses prepared unto battle;        and on their heads [were] as it were crowns like gold, and        their faces [were] as the faces of men. 
{9:8} And they had        hair as the hair of women, and their teeth were as [the teeth]        of lions. 
{9:9} And they had breastplates, as it were        breastplates of iron; and the sound of their wings [was] as        the sound of chariots of many horses running to battle.        
{9:10} And they had tails like unto scorpions, and there        were stings in their tails: and their power [was] to hurt men        five months. 
{9:11} And they had a king over them, [which        is] the angel of the bottomless pit, whose name in the        Hebrew tongue [is] Abaddon, but in the Greek tongue hath        [his] name Apollyon. 
{9:12} One woe is past; [and,]        behold, there come two woes more hereafter.        
{9:13} And the sixth angel sounded, and I heard a voice        from the four horns of the golden altar which is before God,        
{9:14} Saying to the sixth angel which had the trumpet,        Loose the four angels which are bound in the great river        Euphrates. 
{9:15} And the four angels were loosed, which        were prepared for an hour, and a day, and a month, and a        year, for to slay the third part of men. 
{9:16} And the        number of the army of the horsemen [were] two hundred        thousand thousand: and I heard the number of them. 
{9:17}        And thus I saw the horses in the vision, and them that sat on        them, having breastplates of fire, and of jacinth, and        brimstone: and the heads of the horses [were] as the heads        of lions; and out of their mouths issued fire and smoke and        brimstone. 
{9:18} By these three was the third part of men        killed, by the fire, and by the smoke, and by the brimstone,        which issued out of their mouths. 
{9:19} For their power is        in their mouth, and in their tails: for their tails [were] like        unto serpents, and had heads, and with them they do hurt.        
{9:20} And the rest of the men which were not killed by        these plagues yet repented not of the works of their hands,        that they should not worship devils, and idols of gold, and        silver, and brass, and stone, and of wood: which neither can        see, nor hear, nor walk: 
{9:21} Neither repented they of        their murders, nor of their sorceries, nor of their fornication,        nor of their thefts.        
{10:1} And I saw another mighty angel come down from        heaven, clothed with a cloud: and a rainbow [was] upon his        head, and his face [was] as it were the sun, and his feet as        pillars of fire: 
{10:2} And he had in his hand a little book        open: and he set his right foot upon the sea, and [his] left        [foot] on the earth, 
{10:3} And cried with a loud voice, as        [when] a lion roareth: and when he had cried, seven        thunders uttered their voices. 
{10:4} And when the seven        thunders had uttered their voices, I was about to write: and I        heard a voice from heaven saying unto me, Seal up those        things which the seven thunders uttered, and write them not.        
{10:5} And the angel which I saw stand upon the sea and        upon the earth lifted up his hand to heaven, 
{10:6} And        sware by him that liveth for ever and ever, who created        heaven, and the things that therein are, and the earth, and        the things that therein are, and the sea, and the things which        are therein, that there should be time no longer: 
{10:7} But        in the days of the voice of the seventh angel, when he shall        begin to sound, the mystery of God should be finished, as        he hath declared to his servants the prophets. 
{10:8} And        the voice which I heard from heaven spake unto me again,        and said, Go [and] take the little book which is open in the        hand of the angel which standeth upon the sea and upon the        earth. 
{10:9} And I went unto the angel, and said unto him,        Give me the little book. And he said unto me, Take [it,] and        eat it up; and it shall make thy belly bitter, but it shall be in        thy mouth sweet as honey. 
{10:10} And I took the little        book out of the angel’s hand, and ate it up; and it was in my        mouth sweet as honey: and as soon as I had eaten it, my        belly was bitter. 
{10:11} And he said unto me, Thou must        prophesy again before many peoples, and nations, and        tongues, and kings.        
{11:1} And there was given me a reed like unto a rod: and        the angel stood, saying, Rise, and measure the temple of        God, and the altar, and them that worship therein. 
{11:2}        But the court which is without the temple leave out, and        measure it not; for it is given unto the Gentiles: and the holy        city shall they tread under foot forty [and] two months.        
{11:3} And I will give [power] unto my two witnesses, and        they shall prophesy a thousand two hundred [and]        threescore days, clothed in sackcloth. 
{11:4} These are the        two olive trees, and the two candlesticks standing before the        God of the earth. 
{11:5} And if any man will hurt them, fire        proceedeth out of their mouth, and devoureth their enemies:        and if any man will hurt them, he must in this manner be        killed. 
{11:6} These have power to shut heaven, that it rain        not in the days of their prophecy: and have power over        waters to turn them to blood, and to smite the earth with all        plagues, as often as they will. 
{11:7} And when they shall        have finished their testimony, the beast that ascendeth out of        the bottomless pit shall make war against them, and shall        overcome them, and kill them. 
{11:8} And their dead        bodies [shall lie] in the street of the great city, which        spiritually is called Sodom and Egypt, where also our Lord        was crucified. 
{11:9} And they of the people and kindreds        and tongues and nations shall see their dead bodies three        days and an half, and shall not suffer their dead bodies to be        put in graves. 
{11:10} And they that dwell upon the earth        shall rejoice over them, and make merry, and shall send        gifts one to another; because these two prophets tormented        them that dwelt on the earth. 
{11:11} And after three days        and an half the Spirit of life from God entered into them,        and they stood upon their feet; and great fear fell upon them        which saw them. 
{11:12} And they heard a great voice from        heaven saying unto them, Come up hither. And they        ascended up to heaven in a cloud; and their enemies beheld        them. 
{11:13} And the same hour was there a great        earthquake, and the tenth part of the city fell, and in the        earthquake were slain of men seven thousand: and the        remnant were affrighted, and gave glory to the God of        heaven. 
{11:14} The second woe is past; [and,] behold, the        third woe cometh quickly. 
{11:15} And the seventh angel        sounded; and there were great voices in heaven, saying, The        kingdoms of this world are become [the kingdoms] of our        Lord, and of his Christ; and he shall reign for ever and ever.        
{11:16} And the four and twenty elders, which sat before        God on their seats, fell upon their faces, and worshipped        God, 
{11:17} Saying, We give thee thanks, O Lord God        Almighty, which art, and wast, and art to come; because        thou hast taken to thee thy great power, and hast reigned.        
{11:18} And the nations were angry, and thy wrath is come,        and the time of the dead, that they should be judged, and        that thou shouldest give reward unto thy servants the        prophets, and to the saints, and them that fear thy name,        small and great; and shouldest destroy them which destroy        the earth. 
{11:19} And the temple of God was opened in        heaven, and there was seen in his temple the ark of his        testament: and there were lightnings, and voices, and        thunderings, and an earthquake, and great hail.       
</book>     
<book name = "Revelations">        
{21:1} And I saw a new heaven and a new earth: for the        first heaven and the first earth were passed away; and there        was no more sea. 
{21:2} And I John saw the holy city, new        Jerusalem, coming down from God out of heaven, prepared        as a bride adorned for her husband. 
{21:3} And I heard a        great voice out of heaven saying, Behold, the tabernacle of        God [is] with men, and he will dwell with them, and they        shall be his people, and God himself shall be with them,        [and be] their God. 
{21:4} And God shall wipe away all        tears from their eyes; and there shall be no more death,        neither sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more        pain: for the former things are passed away. 
{21:5} And he        that sat upon the throne said, Behold, I make all things new.        And he said unto me, Write: for these words are true and        faithful. 
{21:6} And he said unto me, It is done. I am Alpha        and Omega, the beginning and the end. I will give unto him        that is athirst of the fountain of the water of life freely.        
{21:7} He that overcometh shall inherit all things; and I will        be his God, and he shall be my son. 
{21:8} But the fearful,        and unbelieving, and the abominable, and murderers, and        whoremongers, and sorcerers, and idolaters, and all liars,        shall have their part in the lake which burneth with fire and        brimstone: which is the second death.        
{21:9} And there came unto me one of the seven angels        which had the seven vials full of the seven last plagues, and        talked with me, saying, Come hither, I will shew thee the        bride, the Lamb’s wife. 
{21:10} And he carried me away in        the spirit to a great and high mountain, and shewed me that        great city, the holy Jerusalem, descending out of heaven        from God, 
{21:11} Having the glory of God: and her light        [was] like unto a stone most precious, even like a jasper        stone, clear as crystal; 
{21:12} And had a wall great and        high, [and] had twelve gates, and at the gates twelve angels,        and names written thereon, which are [the names] of the        twelve tribes of the children of Israel: 
{21:13} On the east        three gates; on the north three gates; on the south three        gates; and on the west three gates. 
{21:14} And the wall of        the city had twelve foundations, and in them the names of        the twelve apostles of the Lamb. 
{21:15} And he that talked        with me had a golden reed to measure the city, and the gates        thereof, and the wall thereof. 
{21:16} And the city lieth        foursquare, and the length is as large as the breadth: and he        measured the city with the reed, twelve thousand furlongs.        The length and the breadth and the height of it are equal.        
{21:17} And he measured the wall thereof, an hundred        [and] forty [and] four cubits, [according to] the measure of a        man, that is, of the angel. 
{21:18} And the building of the        wall of it was [of] jasper: and the city [was] pure gold, like        unto clear glass. 
{21:19} And the foundations of the wall of        the city [were] garnished with all manner of precious stones.        The first foundation [was] jasper; the second, sapphire; the        third, a chalcedony; the fourth, an emerald; 
{21:20} The        fifth, sardonyx; the sixth, sardius; the seventh, chrysolite;        the eighth, beryl; the ninth, a topaz; the tenth, a        chrysoprasus; the eleventh, a jacinth; the twelfth, an        amethyst. 
{21:21} And the twelve gates [were] twelve        pearls; every several gate was of one pearl: and the street of        the city [was] pure gold, as it were transparent glass.        
{21:22} And I saw no temple therein: for the Lord God        Almighty and the Lamb are the temple of it. 
{21:23} And        the city had no need of the sun, neither of the moon, to        shine in it: for the glory of God did lighten it, and the Lamb        [is] the light thereof. 
{21:24} And the nations of them        which are saved shall walk in the light of it: and the kings of        the earth do bring their glory and honour into it. 
{21:25}        And the gates of it shall not be shut at all by day: for there        shall be no night there. 
{21:26} And they shall bring the        glory and honour of the nations into it. 
{21:27} And there        shall in no wise enter into it any thing that defileth, neither        [whatsoever] worketh abomination, or [maketh] a lie: but        they which are written in the Lamb’s book of life.        
{22:1} And he shewed me a pure river of water of life,        clear as crystal, proceeding out of the throne of God and of        the Lamb. 
{22:2} In the midst of the street of it, and on        either side of the river, [was there] the tree of life, which        bare twelve [manner] of fruits, [and] yielded her fruit every        month: and the leaves of the tree [were] for the healing of        the nations. 
{22:3} And there shall be no more curse: but        the throne of God and of the Lamb shall be in it; and his        servants shall serve him: 
{22:4} And they shall see his face;        and his name [shall be] in their foreheads. 
{22:5} And there        shall be no night there; and they need no candle, neither        light of the sun; for the Lord God giveth them light: and        they shall reign for ever and ever.        
{22:6} And he said unto me, These sayings [are] faithful        and true: and the Lord God of the holy prophets sent his        angel to shew unto his servants the things which must        shortly be done. 
{22:7} Behold, I come quickly: blessed is        he that keepeth the sayings of the prophecy of this book.        
{22:8} And I John saw these things, and heard [them.] And        when I had heard and seen, I fell down to worship before        the feet of the angel which shewed me these things. 
{22:9}        Then saith he unto me, See [thou do it] not: for I am thy        fellowservant, and of thy brethren the prophets, and of them        which keep the sayings of this book: worship God. 
{22:10}        And he saith unto me, Seal not the sayings of the prophecy        of this book: for the time is at hand. 
{22:11} He that is        unjust, let him be unjust still: and he which is filthy, let him        be filthy still: and he that is righteous, let him be righteous        still: and he that is holy, let him be holy still. 
{22:12} And,        behold, I come quickly; and my reward [is] with me, to give        every man according as his work shall be. 
{22:13} I am        Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end, the first and        the last. 
{22:14} Blessed [are] they that do his        commandments, that they may have right to the tree of life,        and may enter in through the gates into the city. 
{22:15}        For without [are] dogs, and sorcerers, and whoremongers,        and murderers, and idolaters, and whosoever loveth and        maketh a lie.        
{22:16} I Jesus have sent mine angel to testify unto you        these things in the churches. I am the root and the offspring        of David, [and] the bright and morning star.        
{22:17} And the Spirit and the bride say, Come. And let        him that heareth say, Come. And let him that is athirst        come. And whosoever will, let him take the water of life        freely.        
{22:18} For I testify unto every man that heareth the        words of the prophecy of this book, If any man shall add        unto these things, God shall add unto him the plagues that        are written in this book: 
{22:19} And if any man shall take        away from the words of the book of this prophecy, God        shall take away his part out of the book of life, and out of        the holy city, and [from] the things which are written in this        book.        
{22:20} He which testifieth these things saith, Surely I        come quickly. Amen. Even so, come, Lord Jesus.        
</book>        


<story>Abraham
</story>    
<book name = "Hebrews">        
{11:8} By faith        Abraham, when he was called to go out into a place which        he should after receive for an inheritance, obeyed; and he        went out, not knowing whither he went. 
{11:9} By faith he        sojourned in the land of promise, as [in] a strange country,        dwelling in tabernacles with Isaac and Jacob, the heirs with        him of the same promise: 
{11:10} For he looked for a city        which hath foundations, whose builder and maker [is] God.    
</book>     
<book name = "James">        
{2:21} Was not Abraham our father        justified by works, when he had offered Isaac his son upon        the altar?     
</book>
</Christian-Scripture>