
<?xml-model href="texts-schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<doc name = "Christian Scripture">    
<story s_name="Jesus"> 
<book name="Luke">         
	<verse number = "1:1"> Forasmuch as many have taken in hand to <worship recipient="god">set forth in order a declaration of those things which are most surely believed among us</worship>,        
	</verse><verse number = "1:2"> Even as they delivered them unto us, which from the beginning were eyewitnesses, and ministers of the word; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:3"> It seemed good to me also, having had perfect understanding of all things from the very first, to write unto thee in order, most excellent Theophilus,        
	</verse><verse number = "1:4"> <god characterization="creator">That thou mightest know the certainty of those things</god>, wherein thou hast been instructed. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:5"> There was in the days of Herod, the king of Judaea, a certain priest named Zacharias, of the course of Abia: and his wife [was] of the daughters of Aaron, and her name [was] Elisabeth. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:6"> <god characterization="other-positive">And they were both righteous before God, walking in all the commandments and ordinances of the Lord blameless</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:7"> And they had no child, because that Elisabeth was barren, and they both were [now] well stricken in years. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:8"> And it came to pass, that<god characterization="other-neutral"> while he executed the priest’s office before God in the order of his course</god>,        
	</verse><verse number = "1:9"> According to the custom of the priest’s office, his lot was to burn incense when he went into the temple of the Lord. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:10"> And the whole <worship recipient="god">multitude of the people were praying without at the time of incense.</worship> 
	</verse><verse number = "1:11"> And there appeared unto him an angel of the Lord standing on the right side of the altar of incense. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:12"> <god descrip="fear of">And when Zacharias saw [him,] he was troubled, and fear fell upon him</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:13"> But the angel <god descrip="fear of">said unto him, Fear not, Zacharias: for thy prayer is heard; and thy wife Elisabeth shall bear thee a son, and thou shalt call his name John</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:14"> And thou shalt have joy and gladness; and many shall rejoice at his birth. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:15"> <god characterization="loving">For he shall be great in the sight of the Lord</god>, and shall drink neither wine nor strong drink; and he shall be filled with the Holy Ghost, even from his mother’s womb. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:16"> <love recipient="god">And many of the children of Israel shall he turn to the Lord their God.</love> 
	</verse><verse number = "1:17"> And he shall go before him <respect recipient="god">in the spirit and power of Elias, to turn the hearts of the fathers to the children, and the disobedient to the wisdom of the just; to make ready a people prepared for the Lord.</respect> 
	</verse><verse number = "1:18"> And Zacharias said unto the angel, Whereby shall I know this? for I am an old man, and my wife well stricken in years. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:19"> <respect recipient="god">>And the angel answering said unto him, I am Gabriel, that stand in the presence of God</respect>; and am sent to speak unto thee, and to shew thee these glad tidings. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:20"> <god characterization="wrathful">And, behold, thou shalt be dumb, and not able to speak, until the day that these things shall be performed, because thou believest not my words, which shall be fulfilled in their season.</god> 
	</verse><verse number = "1:21"> And the people waited for Zacharias, and marvelled that he tarried so long in the temple. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:22"> And when he came out, he could not speak unto them: and they perceived that he had seen a vision in the temple: for he beckoned unto them, and remained speechless. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:23"> And it came to pass, that, as soon as the days of his ministration were accomplished, he departed to his own house. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:24"> And after those days his wife Elisabeth conceived, and hid herself five months, saying, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:25"> <love recipient="others">Thus hath the Lord dealt with me in the days wherein he looked on [me,] to take away my reproach among men</love>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:26"> And in the sixth month <god characterization="other-neutral">the angel Gabriel was sent from God unto a city of Galilee, named Nazareth</god>, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:27"> To a virgin espoused to a man whose name was Joseph, of the house of David; and the virgin’s name [was] Mary. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:28"> And the angel came in unto her, and said, <blessings>Hail, [thou that art] highly favoured, the Lord [is] with thee: blessed [art] thou among women</blessings>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:29"> And when she saw [him,] she was troubled at his saying, and cast in her mind what manner of salutation this should be.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:30"> And the angel said unto her, <god descrip="fear of">Fear not, Mary</god>: <god characterization="merciful">for thou hast found favour with God</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:31"> And, behold, thou shalt conceive in thy womb, and bring forth a son, and shalt call his name JESUS. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:32"> <god characterization="powerful">He shall be great, and shall be called the Son of the Highest: and the Lord God shall give unto him the throne of his father David</god>: 
	</verse><verse number = "1:33"> <respect recipient="god">And he shall reign over the house of Jacob for ever; and of his kingdom there shall be no end</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:34"> Then said Mary unto the angel, How shall this be, seeing I know not a man? 
	</verse><verse number = "1:35"> <respect recipient="others">And the angel answered and said unto her, The Holy Ghost shall come upon thee, and the power of the Highest shall overshadow thee: therefore also that holy thing which shall be born of thee shall be called the Son of God</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:36"> And, behold, thy cousin Elisabeth, she hath also conceived a son in her old age: and this is the sixth month with her, who was called barren.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:37"> <god characterization="powerful">For with God nothing shall be impossible</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:38"> And Mary said, Behold the handmaid of the Lord; be it unto me according to thy word. And the angel departed from her. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:39"> And Mary arose in those days, and went into the hill country with haste, into a city of Juda; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:40"> And entered into the house of Zacharias, and saluted Elisabeth. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:41"> And it came to pass, that, <worship recipient="others">when Elisabeth heard the salutation of Mary, the babe leaped in her womb; and Elisabeth was filled with the Holy Ghost</worship>: 
	</verse><verse number = "1:42"> And she spake out with a loud voice, and said, <blessings>Blessed [art] thou among women, and blessed [is] the fruit of thy womb</blessings>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:43"> And whence [is] this to me, that the mother of my Lord should come to me? 
	</verse><verse number = "1:44"> For, lo, as soon as the voice of thy salutation sounded in mine ears, the babe leaped in my womb for joy. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:45"> <blessings>And blessed [is] she that believed: for there shall be a performance of those things which were told her from the Lord</blessings>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:46"> And <worship recipient="god">Mary said, My soul doth magnify the Lord</worship>, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:47"> And <love recipient="god">my spirit hath rejoiced in God my Saviour</love>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:48"> <blessings>For he hath regarded the low estate of his handmaiden: for, behold, from henceforth all generations shall call me blessed</blessings>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:49"> <worship recipient="god">For he that is mighty hath done to me great things; and holy [is] his name</worship>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:50"> And his <god characterization="merciful">mercy</god> [is] on them that <god descrip="fear of">fear him from generation to generation</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:51"> <god characterization="powerful">He hath shewed strength with his arm; he hath scattered the proud in the imagination of their hearts</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:52"> <god characterization="powerful">He hath put down the mighty from [their] seats, and exalted them of low degree</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:53"> <god characterization="loving">He hath filled the hungry with good things; and the rich he hath sent empty away</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:54"> <god characterization="merciful">He hath holpen his servant Israel, in remembrance of [his] mercy</god>; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:55"> As he spake to our fathers, to Abraham, and to his seed for ever. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:56"> And Mary abode with her about three months, and returned to her own house. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:57"> Now Elisabeth’s full time came that she should be delivered; and she brought forth a son. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:58"> And her neighbours and <god characterization="merciful">her cousins heard how the Lord had shewed great mercy upon her; and they rejoiced with her</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:59"> And it came to pass, that on the eighth day they came to circumcise the child; and they called him Zacharias, after the name of his father. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:60"> And his mother answered and said, Not [so;] but he shall be called John. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:61"> And they said unto her, There is none of thy kindred that is called by this name. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:62"> And they made signs to his father, how he would have him called. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:63"> And he asked for a writing table, and wrote, saying, His name is John. And they marvelled all. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:64"> <worship recipient="god">And his mouth was opened immediately, and his tongue [loosed,] and he spake, and praised God</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:65"> <god descrip="fear of">And fear came on all that dwelt round about them: and all these sayings were noised abroad throughout all the hill country of Judaea</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:66"> And all they that heard [them] laid [them] up in their hearts, saying, What manner of child shall this be! And the hand of the Lord was with him. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:67"> And his father Zacharias was filled with the Holy Ghost, and prophesied, saying, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:68"> <blessings>Blessed [be] the Lord God of Israel; for he hath visited and redeemed his people</blessings>, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:69"> And hath raised up an horn of salvation for us in the house of his servant David; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:70"> As he spake by the mouth of his holy prophets, which have been since the world began: 
	</verse><verse number = "1:71"> <god characterization="merciful">That we should be saved from our enemies, and from the hand of all that hate us</god>; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:72"> <god characterization="merciful">To perform the mercy [promised] to our fathers, and to remember his holy covenant</god>; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:73"> The oath which he sware to our father Abraham, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:74"> <god descrip="fear of">That he would grant unto us, that we being delivered out of the hand of our enemies might serve him without fear</god>, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:75"> <respect recipient="god">In holiness and righteousness before him, all the days of our life</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:76"> <respect recipient="others">And thou, child, shalt be called the prophet of the Highest: for thou shalt go before the face of the Lord to prepare his ways</respect>; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:77"> <worship recipient="god">To give knowledge of salvation unto his people by the remission of their sins</worship>, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:78"> <god characterization="merciful">Through the tender mercy of our God; whereby the dayspring from on high hath visited us</god>, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:79"> <god characterization="creator">To give light to them that sit in darkness and [in] the shadow of death, to guide our feet into the way of peace</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:80"> And the child grew, and waxed strong in spirit, and was in the deserts till the day of his shewing unto Israel.</verse>     
</book>    
<book name="Luke"> 
	<verse number = "2:1"> And it came to pass in those days, that there went out a decree from Caesar Augustus, that all the world should be taxed. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:2"> ([And] this taxing was first made when Cyrenius was governor of Syria.) 
	</verse><verse number = "2:3"> And all went to be taxed, every one into his own city. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:4"> And Joseph also went up from Galilee, out of the city of Nazareth, into Judaea, unto the city of David, which is called Bethlehem; (because he was of the house and lineage of David:) 
	</verse><verse number = "2:5"> To be taxed with Mary his espoused wife, being great with child. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:6"> And so it was, that, while they were there, the days were accomplished that she should be delivered. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:7"> And she brought forth her firstborn son, and wrapped him in swaddling clothes, and laid him in a manger; because there was no room for them in the inn. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:8"> And there were in the same country shepherds abiding in the field, keeping watch over their flock by night. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:9"> And, lo, <respect recipient="god">the angel of the Lord came upon them, and the glory of the Lord shone round about them: and they were sore afraid</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:10"> And the angel said unto them, <god descrip="fear of">Fear not</god>: for,<god characterization="loving"> behold, I bring you good tidings of great joy, which shall be to all people</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:11"> For unto you is born this day in the city of David a Saviour, which is Christ the Lord. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:12"> And this [shall be] a sign unto you; Ye shall find the babe wrapped in swaddling clothes, lying in a manger. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:13"> <worship recipient="god">And suddenly there was with the angel a multitude of the heavenly host praising God</worship>, and saying, 
	</verse><verse number = "2:14"> <worship recipient="god">Glory to God in the highest, and on earth peace, good will toward men</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:15"> And it came to pass, as <heaven>the angels were gone away from them into heaven</heaven>, the shepherds said one to another, Let us now go even unto Bethlehem, and see this thing which is come to pass, which the Lord hath made known unto us. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:16"> And they came with haste, and found Mary, and Joseph, and the babe lying in a manger. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:17"> And when they had seen [it,] they made known abroad the saying which was told them concerning this child.        
	</verse><verse number = "2:18"> And all they that heard [it] wondered at those things which were told them by the shepherds. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:19"> But Mary kept all these things, and pondered [them] in her heart. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:20"> <worship recipient="god">And the shepherds returned, glorifying and praising God for all the things that they had heard and seen, as it was told unto them</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:21"> And when eight days were accomplished for the circumcising of the child, his name was called JESUS, which was so named of the angel before he was conceived in the womb. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:22"> <worship recipient="god">And when the days of her purification according to the law of Moses were accomplished, they brought him to Jerusalem, to present [him] to the Lord</worship>; 
	</verse><verse number = "2:23"> (As it is written in the law of the Lord, Every male that openeth the womb shall be called holy to the Lord;) 
	</verse><verse number = "2:24"> And <worship recipient="god">to offer a sacrifice according to that which is said in the law of the Lord, A pair of turtledoves, or two young pigeons</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:25"> And, behold, there was a man in Jerusalem, whose name [was] Simeon; and the same man [was] just and devout, waiting for the consolation of Israel: and the Holy Ghost was upon him. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:26"> <worship recipient="others">And it was revealed unto him by the Holy Ghost, that he should not see death, before he had seen the Lord’s Christ</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:27"> And he came by the Spirit into the temple: and when the parents brought in the child Jesus, to do for him after the custom of the law, 
	</verse><verse number = "2:28"> <blessings>Then took he him up in his arms, and blessed God</blessings>, and said, 
	</verse><verse number = "2:29"> <worship recipient="god">Lord, now lettest thou thy servant depart in peace, according to thy word</worship>: 
	</verse><verse number = "2:30"> <worship recipient="god">For mine eyes have seen thy salvation</worship>, 
	</verse><verse number = "2:31"> Which thou hast prepared before the face of all people; 
	</verse><verse number = "2:32"> A light to lighten the Gentiles, and the glory of thy people Israel. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:33"> And Joseph and his mother marvelled at those things which were spoken of him. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:34"> <blessings>And Simeon blessed them, and said unto Mary his mother</blessings>, <god characterization="creator">Behold, this [child] is set for the fall and rising again of many in Israel; and for a sign which shall be spoken against</god>; 
	</verse><verse number = "2:35"> (Yea, a sword shall pierce through thy own soul also,) that the thoughts of many hearts may be revealed. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:36"> And there was one Anna, a prophetess, the daughter of Phanuel, of the tribe of Aser: she was of a great age, and had lived with an husband seven years from her virginity; 
	</verse><verse number = "2:37"> And she [was] a widow of about fourscore and four years, which departed not from the temple, but <worship recipient="god">served [God] with fastings and prayers night and day</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:38"> And she coming in that instant <worship recipient="god">gave thanks likewise unto the Lord</worship>, and spake of him to all them that looked for redemption in Jerusalem. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:39"> And when they had performed all things according to the law of the Lord, they returned into Galilee, to their own city Nazareth. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:40"> <god characterization="creator">And the child grew, and waxed strong in spirit, filled with wisdom: and the grace of God was upon him</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:41"> Now his parents went to Jerusalem every year at the feast of the passover. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:42"> And when he was twelve years old, they went up to Jerusalem after the custom of the feast. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:43"> And when they had fulfilled the days, as they returned, the child Jesus tarried behind in Jerusalem; and Joseph and his mother knew not [of it. ]
	</verse><verse number = "2:44"> But they, supposing him to have been in the company, went a day’s journey; and they sought him among [their] kinsfolk and acquaintance. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:45"> And when they found him not, they turned back again to Jerusalem, seeking him. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:46"> And it came to pass, that after three days they found him in the temple, sitting in the midst of the doctors, both hearing them, and asking them questions. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:47"> And all that heard him were astonished at his understanding and answers. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:48"> And when they saw him, they were amazed: and his mother said unto him, Son, why hast thou thus dealt with us? behold, thy father and I have sought thee sorrowing. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:49"> And he said unto them, How is it that ye sought me? wist ye not that I must be about my Father’s business? 
	</verse><verse number = "2:50"> And they understood not the saying which he spake unto them. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:51"> And he went down with them, and came to Nazareth, and was subject unto them: but his mother kept all these sayings in her heart. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:52"> And <respect recipient="god">Jesus increased in wisdom and stature, and in favour with God and man</respect>.</verse>     
</book>      
<book name = "John">        
	<verse number = "2:1"> And the third day there was a marriage in Cana of Galilee; and the mother of Jesus was there: 
	</verse><verse number = "2:2"> And both Jesus was called, and his disciples, to the marriage. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:3"> And when they wanted wine, the mother of Jesus saith unto him, They have no wine. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:4"> Jesus saith unto her, Woman, what have I to do with thee? mine hour is not yet come. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:5"> <respect recipient="god">His mother saith unto the servants, Whatsoever he saith unto you, do [it. ]</respect>
	</verse><verse number = "2:6"> And there were set there six waterpots of stone, after the manner of the purifying of the Jews, containing two or three firkins apiece. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:7"> Jesus saith unto them, Fill the waterpots with water. And they filled them up to the brim. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:8"> And he saith unto them, Draw out now, and bear unto the governor of the feast. And they bare [it. ]
	</verse><verse number = "2:9"> When the ruler of the feast had tasted the water that was made wine, and knew not whence it was: (but the servants which drew the water knew;) the governor of the feast called the bridegroom, 
	</verse><verse number = "2:10"> And saith unto him, Every man at the beginning doth set forth good wine; and when men have well drunk, then that which is worse: [but] thou hast kept the good wine until now. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:11"> <worship recipient="god">This beginning of miracles did Jesus in Cana of Galilee, and manifested forth his glory; and his disciples believed on him</worship>.</verse>    
</book>    
<book name = "Matthew">        
	<verse number = "3:13"> Then cometh Jesus from Galilee to Jordan unto John, to be baptized of him. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:14"> But John forbad him, saying, I have need to be baptized of thee, and comest thou to me? 
	</verse><verse number = "3:15"> And Jesus answering said unto him, <god characterization="wrathful">Suffer [it to be so] now: for thus it becometh us to fulfil all righteousness. Then he suffered him</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:16"> And <worship recipient="god">Jesus, when he was baptized, went up straightway out of the water: and, lo, the heavens were opened unto him, and he saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove, and lighting upon him</worship>: 
	</verse><verse number = "3:17"> And lo a voice from <heaven>heaven</heaven>, saying,<god characterization="loving"> This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased</god>.</verse>     
</book>    
<book name = "Luke">        
	<verse number = "8:22"> Now it came to pass on a certain day, that he went into a ship with his disciples: and he said unto them, Let us go over unto the other side of the lake. And they launched forth. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:23"> But as they sailed he fell asleep: and there came down a storm of wind on the lake; and they were filled [with water,] and were in jeopardy. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:24"> And they came to him, <respect recipient="god">and awoke him, saying, Master, master, we perish</respect>. <god characterization="creator">Then he arose, and rebuked the wind and the raging of the water: and they ceased, and there was a calm</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:25"> <god characterization="merciful">And he said unto them, Where is your faith? And they being afraid wondered, saying one to another, What manner of man is this!</god> for <respect recipient="god">he commandeth even the winds and water, and they obey him</respect>.</verse>    
</book> 
<book name = "John">        
	<verse number = "19:1"> Then Pilate therefore took Jesus, and scourged [him. ]
	</verse><verse number = "19:2"> And the soldiers platted a crown of thorns, and put [it] on his head, and they put on him a purple robe,        
	</verse><verse number = "19:3"> And said, Hail, King of the Jews! and they smote him with their hands. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:4"> Pilate therefore went forth again, and saith unto them, Behold, I bring him forth to you, that ye may know that I find no fault in him. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:5"> Then came Jesus forth, wearing the crown of thorns, and the purple robe. And [Pilate] saith unto them, Behold the man!        
	</verse><verse number = "19:6"> When the chief priests therefore and officers saw him, they cried out, saying, Crucify [him,] crucify [him.] Pilate saith unto them, Take ye him, and crucify [him:] for I find no fault in him. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:7"> The Jews answered him, <respect recipient="god">We have a law, and by our law he ought to die, because he made himself the Son of God</respect>.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:8"> When <respect recipient="god">Pilate therefore heard that saying, he was the more afraid</respect>; 
	</verse><verse number = "19:9"> And went again into the judgment hall, and saith unto Jesus, Whence art thou? But Jesus gave him no answer. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:10"> Then saith Pilate unto him, Speakest thou not unto me? knowest thou not that I have power to crucify thee, and have power to release thee?        
	</verse><verse number = "19:11"> Jesus answered, <god characterization="merciful">Thou couldest have no power [at all] against me, except it were given thee from above: therefore he that delivered me unto thee hath the greater sin</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:12"> And from thenceforth Pilate sought to release him: but the Jews cried out, saying, If thou let this man go, thou art not Caesar’s friend: whosoever maketh himself a king speaketh against Caesar.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:13"> When Pilate therefore heard that saying, he brought Jesus forth, and sat down in the judgment seat in a place that is called the Pavement, but in the Hebrew, Gabbatha. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:14"> And it was the preparation of the passover, and about the sixth hour: and he saith unto the Jews, Behold your King! 
	</verse><verse number = "19:15"> But they cried out, Away with [him,] away with [him,] crucify him. Pilate saith unto them, Shall I crucify your King? The chief priests answered, We have no king but Caesar. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:16"> Then delivered he him therefore unto them to be crucified. And they took Jesus, and led [him] away. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:17"> And he bearing his cross went forth into a place called [the place] of a skull, which is called in the Hebrew Golgotha: 
	</verse><verse number = "19:18"> Where they crucified him, and two others with him, on either side one, and Jesus in the midst.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:19"> And Pilate wrote a title, and put [it] on the cross. And the writing was, JESUS OF NAZARETH THE KING OF THE JEWS. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:20"> This title then read many of the Jews: for the place where Jesus was crucified was nigh to the city: and it was written in Hebrew, [and] Greek, [and] Latin. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:21"> Then said the chief priests of the Jews to Pilate, Write not, The King of the Jews; but that he said, I am King of the Jews. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:22"> Pilate answered, What I have written I have written.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:23"> Then the soldiers, when they had crucified Jesus, took his garments, and made four parts, to every soldier a part; and also [his] coat: now the coat was without seam, woven from the top throughout. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:24"> They said therefore among themselves, Let us not rend it, but cast lots for it, whose it shall be: that the scripture might be fulfilled, which saith, They parted my raiment among them, and for my vesture they did cast lots. These things therefore the soldiers did.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:25"> Now there stood by the cross of Jesus his mother, and his mother’s sister, Mary the [wife] of Cleophas, and Mary Magdalene. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:26"> When Jesus therefore saw his mother, and the disciple standing by, whom he loved, he saith unto his mother, Woman, behold thy son! 
	</verse><verse number = "19:27"> <worship recipient="others">Then saith he to the disciple, Behold thy mother! And from that hour that disciple took her unto his own [home. ]</worship>
	</verse><verse number = "19:28"> After this, Jesus knowing that all things were now accomplished, that the scripture might be fulfilled, saith, I thirst. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:29"> Now there was set a vessel full of vinegar: and they filled a spunge with vinegar, and put [it] upon hyssop, and put [it] to his mouth. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:30"> When Jesus therefore had received the vinegar, he said, <god characterization="loving">It is finished: and he bowed his head, and gave up the ghost</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:31"> The Jews therefore, because it was the preparation, that the bodies should not remain upon the cross on the sabbath day, (for that sabbath day was an high day,) besought Pilate that their legs might be broken, and [that] they might be taken away. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:32"> Then came the soldiers, and brake the legs of the first, and of the other which was crucified with him.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:33"> But when they came to Jesus, and saw that he was dead already, they brake not his legs: 
	</verse><verse number = "19:34"> But one of the soldiers with a spear pierced his side, and forthwith came there out blood and water. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:35"> And he that saw [it] bare record, and his record is true: and he knoweth that he saith true, that ye might believe. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:36"> <respect recipient="god">For these things were done, that the scripture should be fulfilled, A bone of him shall not be broken</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:37"> And again another scripture saith, They shall look on him whom they pierced.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:38"> <respect recipient="god">And after this Joseph of Arimathaea, being a disciple of Jesus, but secretly for fear of the Jews, besought Pilate that he might take away the body of Jesus: and Pilate gave [him] leave. He came therefore, and took the body of Jesus</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:39"> And there came also <respect recipient="god">Nicodemus, which at the first came to Jesus by night, and brought a mixture of myrrh and aloes, about an hundred pound [weight. ]</respect>
	</verse><verse number = "19:40"> Then took they the body of Jesus, and wound it in linen clothes with the spices, as the manner of the Jews is to bury.        
	</verse><verse number = "19:41"> Now in the place where he was crucified there was a garden; and in the garden a new sepulchre, wherein was never man yet laid. 
	</verse><verse number = "19:42"> There laid they Jesus therefore because of the Jews’ preparation [day;] for the sepulchre was nigh at hand.</verse>    
</book>     
<book name = "Luke">        
	<verse number = "23:26"> And as they led him away, they laid hold upon one Simon, a Cyrenian, coming out of the country, and on him they laid the cross, that he might bear [it] after Jesus.        
	</verse><verse number = "23:27"> And there followed him a great company of people, and of women, which also bewailed and lamented him. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:28"> But <god characterization="loving">Jesus turning unto them said, Daughters of Jerusalem, weep not for me, but weep for yourselves, and for your children</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:29"> For, behold, the days are coming, in the which they shall say, <blessings>Blessed [are] the barren, and the wombs that never bare, and the paps which never gave suck</blessings>.        
	</verse><verse number = "23:30"> <worship recipient="others">Then shall they begin to say to the mountains, Fall on us; and to the hills, Cover us</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:31"> For if they do these things in a green tree, what shall be done in the dry?        
	</verse><verse number = "23:32"> And there were also two others, malefactors, led with him to be put to death. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:33"> And when they were come to the place, which is called Calvary, there they crucified him, and the malefactors, one on the right hand, and the other on the left.        
	</verse><verse number = "23:34"> Then said <god characterization="merciful">Jesus, Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do. And they parted his raiment, and cast lots</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:35"> And the people stood beholding. And the rulers also with them derided [him,] saying, <god characterization="other-negative">He saved others; let him save himself, if he be Christ, the chosen of God</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:36"> And the soldiers also mocked him, coming to him, and offering him vinegar, 
	</verse><verse number = "23:37"> And saying, If thou be the king of the Jews, save thyself. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:38"> And a superscription also was written over him in letters of Greek, and Latin, and Hebrew, THIS IS THE KING OF THE JEWS.        
	</verse><verse number = "23:39"> And one of the malefactors which were hanged railed on him, saying, If thou be Christ, save thyself and us.        
	</verse><verse number = "23:40"> But the other answering rebuked him, saying, <god descrip="fear of">Dost not thou fear God</god>, seeing thou art in the same condemnation? 
	</verse><verse number = "23:41"> <love recipient="god">And we indeed justly; for we receive the due reward of our deeds: but this man hath done nothing amiss</love>. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:42"> And he said unto <worship recipient="god">Jesus, Lord, remember me when thou comest into thy kingdom</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "23:43"> And Jesus said unto him, <god characterization="loving">Verily I say unto thee, To day shalt thou be with me in paradise</god>.</verse>     
</book>  
<book name = "John">        
	<verse number = "14:6"> <god characterization="creator">Jesus saith unto him, I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "14:7"> <respect recipient="god">If ye had known me, ye should have known my Father also: and from henceforth ye know him, and have seen him</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "14:8"> Philip saith unto him, Lord, shew us the Father, and it sufficeth us.        
	</verse><verse number = "14:9"> Jesus saith unto him, Have I been so long time with you, and yet hast thou not known me, Philip? he that hath seen me hath seen the Father; and how sayest thou [then,] Shew us the Father? 
	</verse><verse number = "14:10"> <respect recipient="god">Believest thou not that I am in the Father, and the Father in me? the words that I speak unto you I speak not of myself: but the Father that dwelleth in me, he doeth the works</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "14:11"> <god characterization="wrathful">Believe me that I [am] in the Father, and the Father in me: or else believe me for the very works’ sake</god>.</verse>     
</book>     
<book name = "Philippians">        
	<verse number = "2:5"> Let this mind be in you, which was also in Christ Jesus: 
	</verse><verse number = "2:6"> <respect recipient="god">Who, being in the form of God, thought it not robbery to be equal with God</respect>: 
	</verse><verse number = "2:7"> <god characterization="creator">But made himself of no reputation, and took upon him the form of a servant, and was made in the likeness of men</god>: 
	</verse><verse number = "2:8"> And being found in fashion as a man, <respect recipient="god">he humbled himself, and became obedient unto death, even the death of the cross</respect>.</verse>     
</book>      
<book name = "Colossians">        
	<verse number = "1:15"> <god characterization="creator">Who is the image of the invisible God, the firstborn of every creature</god>: 
	</verse><verse number = "1:16"> <god characterization="creator">For by him were all things created </god>, <heaven>that are in heaven</heaven>, <god characterization="creator">and that are in earth, visible and invisible, whether [they be] thrones, or dominions, or principalities, or powers: all things were created by him, and for him</god>: 
	</verse><verse number = "1:17"> <god characterization="creator">And he is before all things, and by him all things consist</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:18"> <respect recipient="god">And he is the head of the body, the church: who is the beginning, the firstborn from the dead; that in all [things] he might have the preeminence</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:19"> <worship recipient="god">For it pleased [the Father] that in him should all fulness dwell</worship>; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:20"> And, <god characterization="merciful">having made peace through the blood of his cross, by him to reconcile all things unto himself; by him, [I say,]</god> <heaven>whether [they be] things in earth, or things in heaven</heaven>.</verse>     
</book>    
<book name = "Luke">        
	<verse number = "22:66"> And as soon as it was day, the elders of the people and the chief priests and the scribes came together, and led him into their council, saying, 
	</verse><verse number = "22:67"> Art thou the Christ? tell us. And he said unto them, If I tell you, ye will not believe: 
	</verse><verse number = "22:68"> And if I also ask [you,] ye will not answer me, nor let [me] go. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:69"> <respect recipient="god">Hereafter shall the Son of man sit on the right hand of the power of God</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:70"> <god characterization="other-positive">Then said they all, Art thou then the Son of God? And he said unto them, Ye say that I am</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:71"> And they said, <worship recipient="god">What need we any further witness? for we ourselves have heard of his own mouth</worship>.</verse>       
</book>            
</story>

	
<story s_name="Parables">     
<book name = "Matthew">        
	<verse number = "13:10"> And the disciples came, and said unto him, Why speakest thou unto them in parables? 
	</verse><verse number = "13:11"> He answered and said unto them, <god characterization="creator">Because it is given unto you to know the mysteries of the kingdom of</god> <heaven>heaven</heaven>,<god characterization="creator"> but to them it is not given</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "13:12"> <god characterization="wrathful">For whosoever hath, to him shall be given, and he shall have more abundance: but whosoever hath not, from him shall be taken away even that he hath</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "13:13"> Therefore speak I to them in parables: because they seeing see not; and hearing they hear not, neither do they understand. 
	</verse><verse number = "13:14"> And in them is fulfilled the prophecy of Esaias, which saith, By hearing ye shall hear, and shall not understand; and seeing ye shall see, and shall not perceive: 
	</verse><verse number = "13:15"> <god characterization="merciful">For this people’s heart is waxed gross, and [their] ears are dull of hearing, and their eyes they have closed; lest at any time they should see with [their] eyes, and hear with [their] ears, and should understand with [their] heart, and should be converted, and I should heal them</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "13:16"> <blessings>But blessed [are] your eyes, for they see: and your ears, for they hear</blessings>.</verse>    
</book>            
</story>
	
	
<story s_name="Revelations">
<book name = "Revelations">        
	<verse number = "1:1"> <god characterization="creator">The Revelation of Jesus Christ, which God gave unto him, to shew unto his servants things which must shortly come to pass</god>; and he sent and signified [it] by his angel unto his servant John: 
	</verse><verse number = "1:2"> <god characterization="other-neutral">Who bare record of the word of God, and of the testimony of Jesus Christ</god>, and of all things that he saw. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:3"> <blessings>Blessed [is] he that readeth, and they that hear the words of this prophecy, and keep those things which are written therein: for the time [is] at hand</blessings>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:4"> John to the seven churches which are in Asia: <worship recipient="others">Grace [be] unto you, and peace, from him which is, and which was, and which is to come; and from the seven Spirits which are before his throne</worship>; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:5"> <respect recipient="god">And from Jesus Christ, [who is] the faithful witness, [and] the first begotten of the dead, and the prince of the kings of the earth. Unto him that loved us, and washed us from our sins in his own blood</respect>,        
	</verse><verse number = "1:6"> <worship recipient="god">And hath made us kings and priests unto God and his Father; to him [be] glory and dominion for ever and ever. Amen</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:7"> <worship recipient="god">Behold, he cometh with clouds; and every eye shall see him, and they [also] which pierced him: and all kindreds of the earth shall wail because of him. Even so, Amen</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:8"> <god characterization="powerful">I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the ending, saith the Lord, which is, and which was, and which is to come, the Almighty</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:9"> <respect recipient="god">I John, who also am your brother, and companion in tribulation, and in the kingdom and patience of Jesus Christ, was in the isle that is called Patmos, for the word of God, and for the testimony of Jesus Christ</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:10"> I was in the Spirit on the Lord’s day, and heard behind me a great voice, as of a trumpet, 
	</verse><verse number = "1:11"> Saying, I am Alpha and Omega, the first and the last: and,<god characterization="other-neutral"> What thou seest, write in a book, and send [it] unto the seven churches which are in Asia; unto Ephesus, and unto Smyrna, and unto Pergamos, and unto Thyatira, and unto Sardis, and unto Philadelphia, and unto Laodicea</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:12"> And I turned to see the voice that spake with me. And being turned, I saw seven golden candlesticks; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:13"> And in the midst of the seven candlesticks [one] like unto the Son of man, clothed with a garment down to the foot, and girt about the paps with a golden girdle. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:14"> His head and [his] hairs [were] white like wool, as white as snow; and his eyes [were] as a flame of fire; 
	</verse><verse number = "1:15"> And his feet like unto fine brass, as if they burned in a furnace; and his voice as the sound of many waters. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:16"> And he had in his right hand seven stars: and out of his mouth went a sharp twoedged sword: and his countenance [was] as the sun shineth in his strength. 
	</verse><verse number = "1:17"> <god descrip="fear of">And when I saw him, I fell at his feet as dead. And he laid his right hand upon me, saying unto me, Fear not; I am the first and the last</god>: 
	</verse><verse number = "1:18"> <god characterization="powerful">I [am] he that liveth, and was dead; and, behold, I am alive for evermore, Amen</god>; and <hell>have the keys of hell and of death</hell>.        
	</verse><verse number = "1:19"> Write the things which thou hast seen, and the things which are, and the things which shall be hereafter;        
	</verse><verse number = "1:20"> The mystery of the seven stars which thou sawest in my right hand, and the seven golden candlesticks. The seven stars are the angels of the seven churches: and the seven candlesticks which thou sawest are the seven churches.        
	</verse><verse number = "2:1"> Unto the angel of the church of Ephesus write; These things saith he that holdeth the seven stars in his right hand, who walketh in the midst of the seven golden candlesticks; 
	</verse><verse number = "2:2"> I know thy works, and thy labour, and thy patience, and how thou canst not bear them which are evil: and thou hast tried them which say they are apostles, and are not, and hast found them liars: 
	</verse><verse number = "2:3"> And hast borne, and hast patience, and for my name’s sake hast laboured, and hast not fainted. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:4"> <god characterization="wrathful">Nevertheless I have [somewhat] against thee, because thou hast left thy first love</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:5"> Remember therefore from whence thou art fallen, and repent, and do the first works; or else I will come unto thee quickly, and will remove thy candlestick out of his place, except thou repent. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:6"> But this thou hast, that thou hatest the deeds of the Nicolaitanes, which I also hate.        
	</verse><verse number = "2:7"> <worship recipient="god">He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; To him that overcometh will I give to eat of the tree of life, which is in the midst of the paradise of God</worship>.        
	</verse><verse number = "2:8"> And unto the angel of the church in Smyrna write; These things saith the first and the last, which was dead, and is alive; 
	</verse><verse number = "2:9"> I know thy works, and tribulation, and poverty, (but thou art rich) and [I know] the blasphemy of them which say they are Jews, and are not, but [are] the synagogue of Satan. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:10"> <god descrip="fear of">Fear none of those things which thou shalt suffer</god>: behold, the devil shall cast [some] of you into prison, that ye may be tried; and ye shall have tribulation ten days: be thou faithful unto death, and I will give thee a crown of life. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:11"> He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; He that overcometh shall not be hurt of the second death.        
	</verse><verse number = "2:12"> And to the angel of the church in Pergamos write; These things saith he which hath the sharp sword with two edges; 
	</verse><verse number = "2:13"> I know thy works, and where thou dwellest, [even] where Satan’s seat [is:] and thou holdest fast my name, and hast not denied my faith, even in those days wherein Antipas [was] my faithful martyr, who was slain among you, where Satan dwelleth. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:14"> But I have a few things against thee, because thou hast there them that hold the doctrine of Balaam, who taught Balac to cast a stumblingblock before the children of Israel, to eat things sacrificed unto idols, and to commit fornication. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:15"> So hast thou also them that hold the doctrine of the Nicolaitanes, which thing I hate. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:16"> Repent; or else I will come unto thee quickly, and will fight against them with the sword of my mouth. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:17"> He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; To him that overcometh will I give to eat of the hidden manna, and will give him a white stone, and in the stone a new name written, which no man knoweth saving he that receiveth [it.        ]
	</verse><verse number = "2:18"> And unto the angel of the church in Thyatira write; <god characterization="powerful">These things saith the Son of God, who hath his eyes like unto a flame of fire, and his feet [are] like fine brass</god>;        
	</verse><verse number = "2:19"> I know thy works, and charity, and service, and faith, and thy patience, and thy works; and the last [to be] more than the first. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:20"> Notwithstanding I have a few things against thee, because thou sufferest that woman Jezebel, which calleth herself a prophetess, to teach and to seduce my servants to commit fornication, and to eat things sacrificed unto idols. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:21"> And I gave her space to repent of her fornication; and she repented not. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:22"> Behold, I will cast her into a bed, and them that commit adultery with her into great tribulation, except they repent of their deeds.        
	</verse><verse number = "2:23"> And I will kill her children with death; and all the churches shall know that I am he which searcheth the reins and hearts: and I will give unto every one of you according to your works. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:24"> But unto you I say, and unto the rest in Thyatira, as many as have not this doctrine, and which have not known the depths of Satan, as they speak; I will put upon you none other burden. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:25"> But that which ye have [already] hold fast till I come. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:26"> And he that overcometh, and keepeth my works unto the end, to him will I give power over the nations: 
	</verse><verse number = "2:27"> And he shall rule them with a rod of iron; as the vessels of a potter shall they be broken to shivers: even as I received of my Father.        
	</verse><verse number = "2:28"> And I will give him the morning star. 
	</verse><verse number = "2:29"> He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.        
	</verse><verse number = "3:1"> And unto the angel of the church in Sardis write; <god characterization="other-neutral">These things saith he that hath the seven Spirits of God, and the seven stars; I know thy works, that thou hast a name that thou livest, and art dead</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:2"> <god characterization="wrathful">Be watchful, and strengthen the things which remain, that are ready to die: for I have not found thy works perfect before God</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:3"> Remember therefore how thou hast received and heard, and hold fast, and repent. If therefore thou shalt not watch, I will come on thee as a thief, and thou shalt not know what hour I will come upon thee. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:4"> Thou hast a few names even in Sardis which have not defiled their garments; and they shall walk with me in white: for they are worthy. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:5"> He that overcometh, the same shall be clothed in white raiment; and I will not blot out his name out of the book of life, but I will confess his name before my Father, and before his angels.        
	</verse><verse number = "3:6"> He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.        
	</verse><verse number = "3:7"> And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia write; These things saith he that is holy, he that is true, he that hath the key of David, he that openeth, and no man shutteth; and shutteth, and no man openeth; 
	</verse><verse number = "3:8"> I know thy works: behold, I have set before thee an open door, and no man can shut it: for thou hast a little strength, and hast kept my word, and hast not denied my name. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:9"> Behold, I will make them of the synagogue of Satan, which say they are Jews, and are not, but do lie; behold, I will make them to come and worship before thy feet, and to know that I have loved thee. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:10"> Because thou hast kept the word of my patience, I also will keep thee from the hour of temptation, which shall come upon all the world, to try them that dwell upon the earth. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:11"> Behold, I come quickly: hold that fast which thou hast, that no man take thy crown. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:12"> <god characterization="other-neutral">Him that overcometh will I make a pillar in the temple of my God, and he shall go no more out: and I will write upon him the name of my God, and the name of the city of my God, [which is] new Jerusalem, which cometh down out of</god> <heaven>heaven</heaven> <god characterization="other-neutral">from my God: and [I will write upon him] my new name</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:13"> He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.        
	</verse><verse number = "3:14"> And unto the angel of the church of the Laodiceans write; <god characterization="creator">These things saith the Amen, the faithful and true witness, the beginning of the creation of God</god>;        
	</verse><verse number = "3:15"> I know thy works, that thou art neither cold nor hot: I would thou wert cold or hot. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:16"> So then because thou art lukewarm, and neither cold nor hot, I will spue thee out of my mouth. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:17"> Because thou sayest, I am rich, and increased with goods, and have need of nothing; and knowest not that thou art wretched, and miserable, and poor, and blind, and naked: 
	</verse><verse number = "3:18"> I counsel thee to buy of me gold tried in the fire, that thou mayest be rich; and white raiment, that thou mayest be clothed, and [that] the shame of thy nakedness do not appear; and anoint thine eyes with eyesalve, that thou mayest see. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:19"> As many as I <love recipient="others">love</love>, I rebuke and chasten: be zealous therefore, and repent. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:20"> Behold, I stand at the door, and knock: if any man hear my voice, and open the door, I will come in to him, and will sup with him, and he with me. 
	</verse><verse number = "3:21"> <respect recipient="god">To him that overcometh will I grant to sit with me in my throne, even as I also overcame, and am set down with my Father in his throne</respect>.        
	</verse><verse number = "3:22"> He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.</verse>    
</book>        
<book name = "Revelations">        
	<verse number = "8:1"> And when he had opened the seventh seal, there was silence in <heaven>heaven</heaven> about the space of half an hour. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:2"> <god characterization="powerful">And I saw the seven angels which stood before God</god>; and to them were given seven trumpets. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:3"> And another angel came and stood at the altar, having a golden censer; and there was given unto him much incense, that he should offer [it] with the prayers of all saints upon the golden altar which was before the throne. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:4"> <god characterization="powerful">And the smoke of the incense, [which came] with the prayers of the saints, ascended up before God</god> out of the angel’s hand. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:5"> And the angel took the censer, and filled it with fire of the altar, and cast [it] into the earth: and there were voices, and thunderings, and lightnings, and an earthquake. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:6"> And the seven angels which had the seven trumpets prepared themselves to sound.        
	</verse><verse number = "8:7"> The first angel sounded, and there followed hail and fire mingled with blood, and they were cast upon the earth: and the third part of trees was burnt up, and all green grass was burnt up. 
	</verse><verse number = "8:8"> And the second angel sounded, and as it were a great mountain burning with fire was cast into the sea: and the third part of the sea became blood; 
	</verse><verse number = "8:9"> And the third part of the creatures which were in the sea, and had life, died; and the third part of the ships were destroyed.        
	</verse><verse number = "8:10"> And the third angel sounded, and there fell a great star from <heaven>heaven</heaven>, burning as it were a lamp, and it fell upon the third part of the rivers, and upon the fountains of waters;        
	</verse><verse number = "8:11"> <god characterization="wrathful">And the name of the star is called Wormwood: and the third part of the waters became wormwood; and many men died of the waters, because they were made bitter</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "8:12"> And the fourth angel sounded, and the third part of the sun was smitten, and the third part of the moon, and the third part of the stars; so as the third part of them was darkened, and the day shone not for a third part of it, and the night likewise.        
	</verse><verse number = "8:13"> And I beheld, and heard an angel flying through the midst of <heaven>heaven</heaven>, saying with a loud voice, <god characterization="wrathful">Woe, woe, woe, to the inhabiters of the earth by reason of the other voices of the trumpet of the three angels, which are yet to sound</god>!        
	</verse><verse number = "9:1"> And the fifth angel sounded, and I saw a star fall from <heaven>heaven</heaven> unto the earth: and to him was given the key of the bottomless pit. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:2"> And he opened the bottomless pit; and there arose a smoke out of the pit, as the smoke of a great furnace; and the sun and the air were darkened by reason of the smoke of the pit. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:3"> And there came out of the smoke locusts upon the earth: and unto them was given power, as the scorpions of the earth have power. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:4"> <god characterization="wrathful">And it was commanded them that they should not hurt the grass of the earth, neither any green thing, neither any tree; but only those men which have not the seal of God in their foreheads</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:5"> <god characterization="wrathful">And to them it was given that they should not kill them, but that they should be tormented five months: and their torment [was] as the torment of a scorpion, when he striketh a man</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:6"> <god characterization="wrathful">And in those days shall men seek death, and shall not find it; and shall desire to die, and death shall flee from them</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:7"> And the shapes of the locusts [were] like unto horses prepared unto battle; and on their heads [were] as it were crowns like gold, and their faces [were] as the faces of men. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:8"> And they had hair as the hair of women, and their teeth were as [the teeth] of lions. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:9"> And they had breastplates, as it were breastplates of iron; and the sound of their wings [was] as the sound of chariots of many horses running to battle.        
	</verse><verse number = "9:10"> And they had tails like unto scorpions, and there were stings in their tails: and their power [was] to hurt men five months. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:11"> And they had a king over them, [which is] the angel of the bottomless pit, whose name in the Hebrew tongue [is] Abaddon, but in the Greek tongue hath [his] name Apollyon. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:12"> <god characterization="wrathful">One woe is past; [and,] behold, there come two woes more hereafter</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "9:13"> And the sixth angel sounded, and <god characterization="powerful">I heard a voice from the four horns of the golden altar which is before God</god>,        
	</verse><verse number = "9:14"> Saying to the sixth angel which had the trumpet, Loose the four angels which are bound in the great river Euphrates. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:15"> <god characterization="wrathful">And the four angels were loosed, which were prepared for an hour, and a day, and a month, and a year, for to slay the third part of men</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:16"> And the number of the army of the horsemen [were] two hundred thousand thousand: and I heard the number of them. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:17"> And thus I saw the horses in the vision, and them that sat on them, having breastplates of fire, and of jacinth, and brimstone: and the heads of the horses [were] as the heads of lions; and out of their mouths issued fire and smoke and brimstone. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:18"> <god characterization="wrathful">By these three was the third part of men killed, by the fire, and by the smoke, and by the brimstone, which issued out of their mouths</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "9:19"> For their power is in their mouth, and in their tails: for their tails [were] like unto serpents, and had heads, and with them they do hurt.        
	</verse><verse number = "9:20"> <worship recipient="idols">And the rest of the men which were not killed by these plagues yet repented not of the works of their hands, that they should not worship devils, and idols of gold, and silver, and brass, and stone, and of wood: which neither can see, nor hear, nor walk</worship>: 
	</verse><verse number = "9:21"> Neither repented they of their murders, nor of their sorceries, nor of their fornication, nor of their thefts.        
	</verse><verse number = "10:1"> And I saw another mighty angel come down from <heaven>heaven</heaven>, clothed with a cloud: and a rainbow [was] upon his head, and his face [was] as it were the sun, and his feet as pillars of fire: 
	</verse><verse number = "10:2"> And he had in his hand a little book open: and he set his right foot upon the sea, and [his] left [foot] on the earth, 
	</verse><verse number = "10:3"> And cried with a loud voice, as [when] a lion roareth: and when he had cried, seven thunders uttered their voices. 
	</verse><verse number = "10:4"> And when the seven thunders had uttered their voices, I was about to write: and I heard a voice from <heaven>heaven</heaven> saying unto me, Seal up those things which the seven thunders uttered, and write them not.        
	</verse><verse number = "10:5"> And the angel which I saw stand upon the sea and upon the earth lifted up his hand to <heaven>heaven</heaven>, 
	</verse><verse number = "10:6"> <god characterization="creator">And sware by him that liveth for ever and ever, who created</god> <heaven>heaven</heaven>, <god characterization="wrathful">and the things that therein are, and the earth, and the things that therein are, and the sea, and the things which are therein, that there should be time no longer</god>: 
	</verse><verse number = "10:7"> But in the days of the voice of the seventh angel, when he shall begin to sound, <god characterization="wrathful">the mystery of God should be finished, as he hath declared to his servants the prophets</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "10:8"> And the voice which I heard from <heaven>heaven</heaven> spake unto me again, and said, Go [and] take the little book which is open in the hand of the angel which standeth upon the sea and upon the earth. 
	</verse><verse number = "10:9"> And I went unto the angel, and said unto him, Give me the little book. And he said unto me, Take [it,] and eat it up; and it shall make thy belly bitter, but it shall be in thy mouth sweet as honey. 
	</verse><verse number = "10:10"> And I took the little book out of the angel’s hand, and ate it up; and it was in my mouth sweet as honey: and as soon as I had eaten it, my belly was bitter. 
	</verse><verse number = "10:11"> And he said unto me, Thou must prophesy again before many peoples, and nations, and tongues, and kings.        
	</verse><verse number = "11:1"> And there was given me a reed like unto a rod: and the angel stood, saying, <respect recipient="god">Rise, and measure the temple of God</respect>, and the altar, and them that worship therein. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:2"> But the court which is without the temple leave out, and measure it not; for it is given unto the Gentiles: and the holy city shall they tread under foot forty [and] two months.        
	</verse><verse number = "11:3"> <god characterization="powerful">And I will give [power] unto my two witnesses, and they shall prophesy a thousand two hundred [and] threescore days, clothed in sackcloth</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:4"> These are the <god characterization="creator">two olive trees, and the two candlesticks standing before the God of the earth</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:5"> <god characterization="wrathful">And if any man will hurt them, fire proceedeth out of their mouth, and devoureth their enemies: and if any man will hurt them, he must in this manner be killed</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:6"> These have power to shut <heaven>heaven</heaven>, that it rain not in the days of their prophecy: and have power over waters to turn them to blood, and to smite the earth with all plagues, as often as they will. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:7"> <god characterization="wrathful">And when they shall have finished their testimony, the beast that ascendeth out of the bottomless pit shall make war against them, and shall overcome them, and kill them</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:8"> <god characterization="wrathful">And their dead bodies [shall lie] in the street of the great city, which spiritually is called Sodom and Egypt, where also our Lord was crucified</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:9"> And they of the people and kindreds and tongues and nations shall see their dead bodies three days and an half, and shall not suffer their dead bodies to be put in graves. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:10"> And they that dwell upon the earth shall rejoice over them, and make merry, and shall send gifts one to another; because these two prophets tormented them that dwelt on the earth. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:11"> <god characterization="creator">And after three days and an half the Spirit of life from God entered into them, and they stood upon their feet</god>; and <god descrip="fear of">great fear fell upon them which saw them</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:12"> And they heard a great voice from <heaven>heaven</heaven> saying unto them, Come up hither. And they ascended up to <heaven>heaven</heaven> in a cloud; and their enemies beheld them. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:13"> <god characterization="wrathful">And the same hour was there a great earthquake, and the tenth part of the city fell, and in the earthquake were slain of men seven thousand: and the remnant were affrighted, and gave glory to the God of</god>        <heaven>heaven</heaven>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:14"> The second woe is past; [and,] behold, the third woe cometh quickly. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:15"> And the seventh angel sounded; and there were great voices in <heaven>heaven</heaven>, saying, <god characterization="powerful">The kingdoms of this world are become [the kingdoms] of our Lord, and of his Christ; and he shall reign for ever and ever</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "11:16"> And the four and twenty elders,<worship recipient="god"> which sat before God on their seats, fell upon their faces, and worshipped God </worship>, 
	</verse><verse number = "11:17"> Saying, <worship recipient="god">We give thee thanks, O Lord God Almighty, which art, and wast, and art to come; because thou hast taken to thee thy great power, and hast reigned</worship>.        
	</verse><verse number = "11:18"> And the nations were angry, and thy wrath is come, and the time of the dead, that they should be judged, and that thou shouldest give reward unto thy servants the prophets, and to the saints, and <god descrip="fear of">them that fear thy name</god>, small and great; and shouldest destroy them which destroy the earth. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:19"> <god characterization="wrathful">And the temple of God was opened in</god> <heaven>heaven</heaven>,<god characterization="wrathful"> and there was seen in his temple the ark of his testament: and there were lightnings, and voices, and thunderings, and an earthquake, and great hail</god>.</verse>       
</book>     
<book name = "Revelations">        
	<verse number = "21:1"> And I saw a new <heaven>heaven</heaven> and a new earth: for the first <heaven>heaven</heaven> and the first earth were passed away; and there was no more sea. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:2"> <god characterization="powerful">And I John saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down from God out of </god><heaven>heaven</heaven>, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:3"> And I heard a great voice out of <heaven>heaven</heaven> saying, <god characterization="merciful">Behold, the tabernacle of God [is] with men, and he will dwell with them, and they shall be his people, and God himself shall be with them, [and be] their God</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:4"> <god characterization="loving">And God shall wipe away all tears from their eyes; and there shall be no more death, neither sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain: for the former things are passed away</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:5"> And he that sat upon the throne said, <god characterization="creator">Behold, I make all things new. And he said unto me, Write: for these words are true and faithful</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:6"> And he said unto me, It is done.<god characterization="creator"> I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end. I will give unto him that is athirst of the fountain of the water of life freely</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "21:7"> <god characterization="creator">He that overcometh shall inherit all things; and I will be his God, and he shall be my son</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:8"> <god characterization="wrathful">But the fearful, and unbelieving, and the abominable, and murderers, and whoremongers, and sorcerers, and idolaters, and all liars, shall have their part in the lake which burneth with fire and brimstone: which is the second death</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "21:9"> And there came unto me one of the seven angels which had the seven vials full of the seven last plagues, and talked with me, saying, Come hither, I will shew thee the bride, the Lamb’s wife. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:10"> And he carried me away in the spirit to a great and high mountain, and <god characterization="other-neutral">shewed me that great city, the holy Jerusalem, descending out of</god> <heaven>heaven</heaven><god characterization="other-neutral"> from God</god>, 
	</verse><verse number = "21:11"> <god characterization="loving">Having the glory of God: and her light [was] like unto a stone most precious, even like a jasper stone, clear as crystal</god>; 
	</verse><verse number = "21:12"> <respect recipient="others">And had a wall great and high, [and] had twelve gates, and at the gates twelve angels, and names written thereon, which are [the names] of the twelve tribes of the children of Israel</respect>: 
	</verse><verse number = "21:13"> On the east three gates; on the north three gates; on the south three gates; and on the west three gates. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:14"> <respect recipient="others">And the wall of the city had twelve foundations, and in them the names of the twelve apostles of the Lamb</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:15"> And he that talked with me had a golden reed to measure the city, and the gates thereof, and the wall thereof. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:16"> And the city lieth foursquare, and the length is as large as the breadth: and he measured the city with the reed, twelve thousand furlongs. The length and the breadth and the height of it are equal.        
	</verse><verse number = "21:17"> And he measured the wall thereof, an hundred [and] forty [and] four cubits, [according to] the measure of a man, that is, of the angel. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:18"> And the building of the wall of it was [of] jasper: and the city [was] pure gold, like unto clear glass. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:19"> And the foundations of the wall of the city [were] garnished with all manner of precious stones. The first foundation [was] jasper; the second, sapphire; the third, a chalcedony; the fourth, an emerald; 
	</verse><verse number = "21:20"> The fifth, sardonyx; the sixth, sardius; the seventh, chrysolite; the eighth, beryl; the ninth, a topaz; the tenth, a chrysoprasus; the eleventh, a jacinth; the twelfth, an amethyst. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:21"> And the twelve gates [were] twelve pearls; every several gate was of one pearl: and the street of the city [was] pure gold, as it were transparent glass.        
	</verse><verse number = "21:22"> <god characterization="powerful">And I saw no temple therein: for the Lord God Almighty and the Lamb are the temple of it</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:23"> <god characterization="powerful">And the city had no need of the sun, neither of the moon, to shine in it: for the glory of God did lighten it, and the Lamb [is] the light thereof</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:24"> <worship recipient="god">And the nations of them which are saved shall walk in the light of it: and the kings of the earth do bring their glory and honour into it</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:25"> And the gates of it shall not be shut at all by day: for there shall be no night there. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:26"> <god characterization="loving">And they shall bring the glory and honour of the nations into it</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "21:27"> And there shall in no wise enter into it any thing that defileth, neither [whatsoever] worketh abomination, or [maketh] a lie: but they which are written in the Lamb’s book of life.        
	</verse><verse number = "22:1"> <god characterization="powerful">And he shewed me a pure river of water of life, clear as crystal, proceeding out of the throne of God and of the Lamb</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:2"> In the midst of the street of it, and on either side of the river, [was there] the tree of life, which bare twelve [manner] of fruits, [and] yielded her fruit every month: and the leaves of the tree [were] for the healing of the nations. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:3"> And there shall be no more curse: <respect recipient="god">but the throne of God and of the Lamb shall be in it; and his servants shall serve him</respect>: 
	</verse><verse number = "22:4"> And they shall see his face; and his name [shall be] in their foreheads. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:5"> And there shall be no night there; and they need no candle, neither light of the sun; <god characterization="creator">for the Lord God giveth them light</god>: and they shall reign for ever and ever.        
	</verse><verse number = "22:6"> And he said unto me, <blessings>These sayings [are] faithful and true: and the Lord God of the holy prophets sent his angel to shew unto his servants the things which must shortly be done</blessings>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:7"> <blessings>Behold, I come quickly: blessed is he that keepeth the sayings of the prophecy of this book</blessings>.        
	</verse><verse number = "22:8"> And I John saw these things, and heard [them.] And when I had heard and seen,<worship recipient="others"> I fell down to worship before the feet of the angel which shewed me these things</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:9"> Then saith he unto me, <worship recipient="god">See [thou do it] not: for I am thy fellowservant, and of thy brethren the prophets, and of them which keep the sayings of this book: worship God</worship>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:10"> And he saith unto me, Seal not the sayings of the prophecy of this book: for the time is at hand. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:11"> <god characterization="wrathful">He that is unjust, let him be unjust still: and he which is filthy, let him be filthy still: and he that is righteous, let him be righteous still: and he that is holy, let him be holy still</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:12"> And, behold, I come quickly; and my reward [is] with me, to give every man according as his work shall be. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:13"> <god characterization="creator">I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end, the first and the last</god>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:14"> <blessings>Blessed [are] they that do his commandments, that they may have right to the tree of life</blessings>, and<heaven> may enter in through the gates into the city</heaven>. 
	</verse><verse number = "22:15"> <god characterization="wrathful">For without [are] dogs, and sorcerers, and whoremongers, and murderers, and idolaters, and whosoever loveth and maketh a lie</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "22:16"> <god characterization="powerful">I Jesus have sent mine angel to testify unto you these things in the churches. I am the root and the offspring of David, [and] the bright and morning star</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "22:17"> <god characterization="loving">And the Spirit and the bride say, Come. And let him that heareth say, Come. And let him that is athirst come. And whosoever will, let him take the water of life freely</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "22:18"> <god characterization="wrathful">For I testify unto every man that heareth the words of the prophecy of this book, If any man shall add unto these things, God shall add unto him the plagues that are written in this book</god>: 
	</verse><verse number = "22:19"> <god characterization="wrathful">And if any man shall take away from the words of the book of this prophecy, God shall take away his part out of the book of life, and out of the holy city, and [from] the things which are written in this book</god>.        
	</verse><verse number = "22:20"> He which testifieth these things saith, Surely I come quickly. Amen. Even so, come, Lord Jesus.</verse>        
</book>        
</story>
	
	
<story s_name="Abraham">   
<book name = "Hebrews">        
	<verse number = "11:8"> <respect recipient="god">By faith Abraham, when he was called to go out into a place which he should after receive for an inheritance, obeyed; and he went out, not knowing whither he went</respect>. 
	</verse><verse number = "11:9"> <respect recipient="god">By faith he sojourned in the land of promise, as [in] a strange country, dwelling in tabernacles with Isaac and Jacob, the heirs with him of the same promise</respect>: 
	</verse><verse number = "11:10"> <god characterization="creator">For he looked for a city which hath foundations, whose builder and maker [is] God</god>.</verse>    
</book>     
<book name = "James">        
	<verse number = "2:21"> <worship recipient="god">Was not Abraham our father justified by works, when he had offered Isaac his son upon the altar</worship>?</verse>     
</book>
</story>
</doc>