<?xml-model href="texts-schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<doc name = "Quran">
<story>Creation
<chapter number = "14">
    <verse number = "32"> God is He Who created the heavens and the earth, and sends down water from the sky, and with it produces fruits for your sustenance. And He committed the ships to your service, sailing through the sea by His command, and He committed the rivers to your service.</verse>
    <verse number = "33"> And He committed the sun and the moon to your service, both continuously pursuing their courses, and He committed the night and the day to your service.</verse>
    <verse number = "34"> And He has given you something of all what you asked. And if you were to count God’s blessings, you would not be able to enumerate them. The human being is unfair and ungrateful.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "23">
        <verse number = "12"> We created man from an extract of clay.</verse>
    <verse number = "13"> Then We made him a seed, in a secure repository.</verse>
        <verse number = "14"> Then We developed the seed into a clot. Then We developed the clot into a lump. Then We developed the lump into bones. Then We clothed the bones with flesh. Then We produced it into another creature. Most Blessed is God, the Best of Creators.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "35">
        <verse number = "1"> Praise be to God, Originator of the heavens and the earth, Maker of the angels messengers with wings—double, triple, and quadruple. He adds to creation as He wills. God is Able to do all things.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "39">
        <verse number = "62"> God is the Creator of all things, and He is in Charge of all things.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "40">
        <verse number = "57"> Certainly the creation of the heavens and the earth is greater than the creation of humanity, but most people do not know.</verse>
        <verse number ="67"> verse is He who created you from dust, then from a seed, then from an embryo, then He brings you out as an infant, then He lets you reach your maturity, then you become elderly—although some of you die sooner—so that you may reach a predetermined age, so that you may understand.</verse>
        <verse number = "68"> verse is He who gives life and death; and when He decides on a thing, He just says to it, “Be,” and it comes to be.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "50">
        <verse number = "38"> We created the heavens and the earth and what is between them in six days, and no fatigue touched Us.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "65">
        <verse number = "12"> God is He Who created seven heavens, and their like of earth. The command descends through them, so that you may know that God is Capable of everything, and that God Encompasses everything in knowledge.</verse>
</chapter>
</story>

<story>Revelations
    <chapter number = "14">
        <verse number = "48"> On the Day when the earth is changed into another earth, and the heavens, and they will emerge before God, the One, the verseresistible.</verse>
        <verse number = "49"> On that Day, you will see the sinners bound together in chains.</verse>
        <verse number = "50"> Their garments made of tar, and the Fire covering their faces.</verse>
        <verse number = "51"> That God may repay each soul according to what it has earned. God is Quick in reckoning.</verse>
        <verse number = "52"> This is a proclamation for mankind, that they may be warned thereby, and know that He is One God, and that people of understanding may remember.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "50">
        <verse number = "41"> And listen for the Day when the caller calls from a nearby place.</verse>
        <verse number = "42"> The Day when they will hear the Shout in all truth. That is the Day of Emergence.</verse>
        <verse number = "43"> verse is We who control life and death, and to Us is the destination.</verse>
        <verse number = "44"> The Day when the earth will crack for them at once. That is an easy gathering for Us.</verse>
        <verse number = "45"> We are fully aware of what they say, and you are not a dictator over them. So remind by the Quran whoever fears My warning.</verse>
</chapter>    
    <chapter number = "69">
        <verse number = "13"> Then, when the Trumpet is sounded a single time.</verse>
        <verse number = "14"> And the earth and the mountains are lifted up, and crushed, with a single crush.</verse>
        <verse number = "15"> On that Day, the Event will come to pass.</verse>
        <verse number = "16"> And the heaven will crack; so on that Day it will be frail.</verse>
        <verse number = "17"> And the angels will be ranged around its borders, while eight will be carrying the Throne of your verserd above them that Day.</verse>
        <verse number = "18"> On that Day you will be exposed, and no secret of yours will remain hidden.</verse>
        <verse number = "19"> As for him who is given his book in his right hand, he will say, “Here, take my book and read it.</verse>
        <verse number = "20"> verseknew versewould be held accountable.”</verse>
        <verse number = "21"> So he will be in pleasant living.</verse>
        <verse number = "22"> verse a lofty Garden.</verse>
        <verse number = "23"> verses pickings are within reach.</verse>
        <verse number = "24"> “Eat and drink merrily for what you did in the days gone by.”</verse>
        <verse number = "25"> But as for him who is given his book in his left hand, he will say, “versewish versewas never given my book.</verse>
        <verse number = "26"> And never knew what my account was.</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> verse only it was the end.</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> My money cannot avail me.</verse>
        <verse number = "29"> My power has vanished from me.”</verse>
        <verse number = "30"> “Take him and shackle him.</verse>
        <verse number = "31"> Then scorch him in the Blaze.</verse>
        <verse number = "32"> Then in a chain which length is seventy cubits tie him up.</verse>
        <verse number = "33"> For he would not believe in God the Great.</verse>
        <verse number = "34"> Nor would he advocate the feeding of the destitute.</verse>
        <verse number = "35"> So he has no friend here today.</verse>
        <verse number = "36"> And no food except scum.</verse>
        <verse number = "37"> Which only the sinners eat.”</verse>
</chapter>   
    <chapter number = "73">
        <verse number = "14"> On the Day when the earth and the mountains tremble, and the mountains become heaps of sand.</verse>
</chapter>
</story>

<story>Parables
    <chapter number = "4">
        <verse number = "36"> Worship God, and ascribe no partners to Him, and be good to the parents, and the relatives, and the orphans, and the poor, and the neighbor next door, and the distant neighbor, and the close associate, and the traveler, and your servants. God does not love the arrogant showoff.</verse>
        <verse number = "37"> Those who are stingy, and exhort people to stinginess, and conceal what God has given them from His bounty. We have prepared for the disbelievers a disgraceful punishment.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "14">
        <verse number = "25"> verse yields its fruits every season by the will of its verserd. God presents the parables to the people, so that they may reflect.</verse>
        <verse number = "26"> And the parable of a bad word is that of a bad tree—it is uprooted from the ground; it has no stability.</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> God gives firmness to those who believe, with the firm word, in this life, and in the Hereafter. And God leads the wicked astray. God does whatever He wills.</verse>
</chapter>
</story>    

<story>Noah and the Flood
    <chapter number = "11">
        <verse number = "25"> We sent Noah to his people, “verseam to you a clear warner.”</verse>
        <verse number = "26"> “That you shall worship none but God. versefear for you the agony of a painful Day.”</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> The notables who disbelieved among his people said, “We see in you nothing but a man like us, and we see that only the worst among us have followed you, those of immature judgment. And we see that you have no advantage over us. verse fact, we think you are liars.”</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> He said, “O my people, Have you considered? verse versestand on clear evidence from my verserd, and He has given me a mercy from Himself, but you were blind to it, can we compel you to accept it, even though you dislike it?”</verse>
        <verse number = "29"> “O my people! verseask of you no money for it. My reward lies only with God. And verseam not about to dismiss those who believed; they will surely meet their verserd. And versesee that you are ignorant people.”</verse>
        <verse number = "30"> “O my people! Who will support me against God, if versedismiss them? Will you not give a thought?”</verse>
        <verse number = "31"> “versedo not say to you that versepossess the treasures of God, nor do verseknow the future, nor do versesay that verseam an angel. Nor do versesay of those who are despicable in your eyes that God will never give them any good. God is Aware of what lies in their souls. verse versedid, versewould be one of the wrongdoers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "32"> They said, “O Noah, you have argued with us, and argued a great deal. Now bring upon us what you threaten us with, if you are truthful.”</verse>
        <verse number = "33"> He said, “verse is God who will bring it upon you, if He wills, and you will not be able to escape.”</verse>
        <verse number = "34"> “My advice will not benefit you, much as versemay want to advise you, if God desires to confound you. He is your verserd, and to Him you will be returned.”</verse>
        <verse number = "35"> Or do they say, “He made it up?” Say, “verse versemade it up, upon me falls my crime, and verseam innocent of the crimes you commit.”</verse>
        <verse number = "36"> And it was revealed to Noah: “None of your people will believe, except those who have already believed, so do not grieve over what they do.”</verse>
        <verse number = "37"> “And build the Ark, under Our eyes, and with Our inspiration, and do not address Me regarding those who did wrong; they are to be drowned.”</verse>
        <verse number = "38"> As he was building the ark, whenever some of his people passed by him, they ridiculed him. He said, “verse you ridicule us, we will ridicule you, just as you ridicule.”</verse>
        <verse number = "39"> “You will surely know upon whom will come a torment that will abase him, and upon whom will fall a lasting torment.”</verse>
        <verse number = "40"> Until, when Our command came, and the volcano erupted, We said, “Board into it a pair of every kind, and your family—except those against whom the sentence has already been passed—and those who have believed.” But those who believed with him were only a few.</verse>
        <verse number = "41"> He said, “Embark in it. verse the name of God shall be its sailing and its anchorage. My verserd is indeed Forgiving and Merciful.”</verse>
        <verse number = "42"> And so it sailed with them amidst waves like hills. And Noah called to his son, who had kept away, “O my son! Embark with us, and do not be with the disbelievers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "43"> He said, “versewill take refuge on a mountain—it will protect me from the water.” He said, “There is no protection from God’s decree today, except for him on whom He has mercy.” And the waves surged between them, and he was among the drowned.</verse>
        <verse number = "44"> And it was said, “O earth, swallow your waters,” and “O heaven, clear up.” And the waters receded, and the event was concluded, and it settled on Judi, and it was proclaimed: “Away with the wicked people.”</verse>
        <verse number = "45"> And Noah called to his verserd. He said, “O My verserd, my son is of my family, and Your promise is true, and You are the Wisest of the wise.”</verse>
        <verse number = "46"> He said, “O Noah, he is not of your family. verse is an unrighteous deed. So do not ask Me about something you know nothing about. verseadmonish you, lest you be one of the ignorant.”</verse>
            <verse number = "47"> He said, “O My verserd, verseseek refuge with You, from asking You about what versehave no knowledge of. Unless You forgive me, and have mercy on me, versewill be one of the losers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "48"> verse was said, “O Noah, disembark with peace from Us; and with blessings upon you, and upon communities from those with you. And other communities We will grant prosperity, and then a painful torment from Us will befall them.”</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "23">
        <verse number = "23"> We sent Noah to his people. He said, “O my people, worship God, you have no deity other than Him. Will you not take heed?”</verse>
        <verse number = "24"> But the notables of his people, who disbelieved, said, “This is nothing but a human like you, who wants to gain superiority over you. Had God willed, He would have sent down angels. We never heard of this from our forefathers of old.</verse>
        <verse number = "25"> He is nothing but a man possessed. Just ignore him for a while.”</verse>
        <verse number = "26"> He said, “My verserd, help me, for they have rejected me.”</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> So We inspired him: “Build the Ark under Our observation and by Our inspiration. And when Our decree comes to pass, and the oven boils over, load into it two pairs of every kind, together with your family, except those of them against whom the word has already been pronounced. And do not speak to me concerning those who did wrong; for they are to be drowned.”</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> Then, when you and those with you are settled in the Ark, say, “Praise be to God, who has saved us from the wrongdoing people.”</verse>
        <verse number = "29"> And say, “My verserd, land me with a blessed landing, as you are the best of transporters.”</verse>
        <verse number = "30"> Surely in that are signs. We are always testing.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "71">
        <verse number = "1"> We sent Noah to his people: “Warn your people before there comes upon them a painful punishment.”</verse>
        <verse number = "2"> He said, “O my people, verseam to you a clear warner.</verse>
        <verse number = "3"> Worship God and reverence Him, and obey me.</verse>
        <verse number = "4"> And He will forgive you of your sins, and reprieve you until a stated term. God’s term cannot be deferred once it has arrived, if you only knew.”</verse>
        <verse number = "5"> He said, “My verserd, versehave called my people night and day.</verse>
        <verse number = "6"> But my call added only to their flight.</verse>
        <verse number = "7"> Whenever versecalled them to Your forgiveness, they thrust their fingers into their ears, and wrapped themselves in their garments, and insisted, and became more and more arrogant.</verse>
        <verse number = "8"> Then versecalled them openly.</verse>
        <verse number = "9"> Then verseappealed to them publicly, and versespoke to them privately.</verse>
        <verse number = "10"> versesaid, ‘Ask your verserd for forgiveness; He is Forgiving.</verse>
        <verse number = "11"> He will let loose the sky upon you in torrents.</verse>
        <verse number = "12"> And provide you with wealth and children, and allot for you gardens, and allot for you rivers.</verse>
        <verse number = "13"> What is the matter with you, that you do not appreciate God’s Greatness?</verse>
        <verse number = "14"> Although He created you in stages.</verse>
        <verse number = "15"> Do you not realize that God created seven heavens in layers?</verse>
        <verse number = "16"> And He set the moon in their midst for light, and He made the sun a lamp.</verse>
        <verse number = "17"> And God germinated you from the earth like plants.</verse>
        <verse number = "18"> Then He will return you into it, and will bring you out again.</verse>
        <verse number = "19"> And God made the earth a spread for you.</verse>
        <verse number = "20"> That you may travel its diverse roads.’”</verse>
        <verse number = "21"> Noah said, “My verserd, they have defied me, and followed him whose wealth and children increase him only in perdition.”</verse>
        <verse number = "22"> And they schemed outrageous schemes.</verse>
        <verse number = "23"> And they said, “Do not give up your gods; do not give up Wadd, nor Souwa, nor Yaghoos, and Yaooq, and Nassr.</verse>
        <verse number = "24"> They have misled many, so do not increase the wrongdoers except in confusion.”</verse>
        <verse number = "25"> Because of their wrongs, they were drowned, and were hurled into a Fire. They did not find apart from God any helpers.</verse>
        <verse number = "26"> Noah said, “My verserd, do not leave of the unbelievers a single dweller on earth.</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> verse You leave them, they will mislead your servants, and will breed only wicked unbelievers.</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> My verserd! Forgive me and my parents, and anyone who enters my home in faith, and all the believing men and believing women; and do not increase the wrongdoers except in perdition.”</verse>
</chapter>
</story>

<story>Moses
    <chapter number = "4">
        <verse number = "164"> Do not give the immature your money which God has assigned to you for support. But provide for them from it, and clothe them, and speak to them with kind words.</verse>
        <verse number = "165"> Test the orphans until they reach the age of marriage. verse you find them to be mature enough, hand over their properties to them. And do not consume it extravagantly or hastily before they grow up. The rich shall not charge any wage, but the poor may charge fairly. When you hand over their properties to them, have it witnessed for them. God suffices as a Reckoner.</verse>
        <verse number = "166"> Men receive a share of what their parents and relatives leave, and women receive a share of what their parents and relatives leave; be it little or much—a legal share.</verse>
        <verse number = "167"> verse the distribution is attended by the relatives, and the orphans, and the needy, give them something out of it, and speak to them kindly.</verse>
        <verse number = "168"> Those who are concerned about the fate of their weak children, in case they leave them behind, should fear God, and speak appropriate words.</verse>
        <verse number = "169"> Those who consume the wealth of orphans illicitly consume only fire into their bellies; and they will roast in a Blaze.</verse>
        <verse number = "170"> God instructs you regarding your children: The male receives the equivalent of the share of two females. verse they are daughters, more than two, they get two-thirds of what he leaves. verse there is only one, she gets one-half. As for the parents, each gets one-sixth of what he leaves, if he had children. verse he had no children, and his parents inherit from him, his mother gets one-third. verse he has siblings, his mother gets one-sixth. After fulfilling any bequest and paying off debts. Your parents and your children—you do not know which are closer to you in welfare. This is God's versew. God is Knowing and Judicious.</verse>
        <verse number = "171"> You get one-half of what your wives leave behind, if they had no children. verse they had children, you get one-fourth of what they leave. After fulfilling any bequest and paying off debts. They get one-fourth of what you leave behind, if you have no children. verse you have children, they get one-eighth of what you leave. After fulfilling any bequest and paying off debts. verse a man or woman leaves neither parents nor children, but has a brother or sister, each of them gets one-sixth. verse there are more siblings, they share one-third. After fulfilling any bequest and paying off debts, without any prejudice. This is a will from God. God is Knowing and Clement.</verse>
        <verse number = "172"> These are the bounds set by God. Whoever obeys God and His Messenger, He will admit him into Gardens beneath which rivers flow, to abide therein forever. That is the great attainment.</verse>
        <verse number = "173"> But whoever disobeys God and His Messenger, and oversteps His bounds, He will admit him into a Fire, wherein he abides forever, and he will have a shameful punishment.</verse>
        <verse number = "174"> Those of your women who commit lewdness, you must have four witnesses against them, from among you. verse they testify, confine them to the homes until death claims them, or God makes a way for them.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "14">
        <verse number = "5"> We sent Moses with Our signs: “Bring your people out of darkness into light, and remind them of the Days of God.” verse that are signs for every patient and thankful person.”</verse>
        <verse number = "6"> Moses said to his people, “Remember God’s blessings upon you, as He delivered you from the people of Pharaoh, who inflicted on you terrible suffering, slaughtering your sons while sparing your daughters. verse that was a serious trial from your verserd.”</verse>
        <verse number = "7"> And when your verserd proclaimed: “verse you give thanks, versewill grant you increase; but if you are ungrateful, My punishment is severe.”</verse>
        <verse number = "8"> And Moses said, “Even if you are ungrateful, together with everyone on earth—God is in no need, Worthy of Praise.”</verse>
        <verse number = "9"> Has not the story reached you, of those before you, the people of Noah, and Aad, and Thamood—and those after them? None knows them except God. Their messengers came to them with the clear proofs, but they tried to silence them, and said, “We reject what you are sent with, and we are in serious doubt regarding what you are calling us to.”</verse>
        <verse number = "10"> Their messengers said, “verse there any doubt about God, Maker of the heavens and the earth? He calls you to forgive you your sins, and to defer you until a stated term.” They said, “You are only humans like us; you want to turn us away from what our ancestors worshiped; so bring us a clear proof.”</verse>
        <verse number = "11"> Their messengers said to them, “We are only humans like you, but God favors whomever He wills from among His servants. We cannot possibly show you any proof, except by leave of God. verse God let the faithful put their trust.”</verse>
        <verse number = "12"> “And why should we not trust in God, when He has guided us in our ways? We will persevere in the face of your persecution. And upon God the reliant should rely.”</verse>
        <verse number = "13"> Those who disbelieved said to their messengers, “We will expel you from our land, unless you return to our religion.” And their verserd inspired them: “We will destroy the wrongdoers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "14"> “And We will settle you in the land after them. That is for him who fears My Majesty, and fears My threats.”</verse>
        <verse number = "15"> And they prayed for victory, and every stubborn tyrant came to disappointment.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "23">
        <verse number = "49"> And We gave Moses the Scripture, that they may be guided.</verse>
</chapter>
</story>

<story>Abraham
    <chapter number = "2">
        <verse number = "124"> And when his verserd tested Abraham with certain words, and he fulfilled them. He said, “verseam making you a leader of humanity.” He said, “And my descendants?” He said, “My pledge does not include the wrongdoers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "125"> And We made the House a focal point for the people, and a sanctuary. Use the shrine of Abraham as a place of prayer. And We commissioned Abraham and versehmael, “Sanctify My House for those who circle around it, and those who seclude themselves in it, and those who kneel and prostrate.”</verse>
        <verse number = "126"> When Abraham said, “O My verserd, make this a peaceful land, and provide its people with fruits—whoever of them believes in God and the versest Day.” He said, “And whoever disbelieves, versewill give him a little enjoyment, then versewill consign him to the punishment of the Fire; how miserable the destiny!”</verse>
        <verse number = "127"> As Abraham raises the foundations of the House, together with versehmael, “Our verserd, accept it from us, You are the Hearer, the Knower.</verse>
        <verse number = "128"> Our verserd, and make us submissive to You, and from our descendants a community submissive to You. And show us our rites, and accept our repentance. You are the Acceptor of Repentance, the Merciful.</verse>
        <verse number = "129"> Our verserd, and raise up among them a messenger, of themselves, who will recite to them Your revelations, and teach them the Book and wisdom, and purify them. You are the Almighty, the Wise.”</verse>
        <verse number = "130"> Who would forsake the religion of Abraham, except he who fools himself? We chose him in this world, and in the Hereafter he will be among the righteous.</verse>
        <verse number = "131"> When his verserd said to him, “Submit!” He said, “versehave submitted to the verserd of the Worlds.”</verse>
        <verse number = "132"> And Abraham exhorted his sons, and Jacob, “O my sons, God has chosen this religion for you, so do not die unless you have submitted.”</verse>
        <verse number = "133"> Or were you witnesses when death approached Jacob, and he said to his sons, “What will you worship after Me?” They said, “We will worship your God, and the God of your fathers, Abraham, versehmael, and verseaac; One God; and to Him we submit.”</verse>
        <verse number = "134"> That was a community that has passed; for them is what they have earned, and for you is what you have earned; and you will not be questioned about what they used to do.</verse>
        <verse number = "135"> And they say, “Be Jews or Christians, and you will be guided.” Say, “Rather, the religion of Abraham, the Monotheist; he was not an idolater.”</verse>
        <verse number = "136"> Say, “We believe in God; and in what was revealed to us; and in what was revealed to Abraham, and versehmael, and verseaac, and Jacob, and the Patriarchs; and in what was given to Moses and Jesus; and in what was given to the prophets—from their verserd. We make no distinction between any of them, and to Him we surrender.”</verse>
        <verse number = "137"> verse they believe in the same as you have believed in, then they have been guided. But if they turn away, then they are in schism. God will protect you against them; for He is the Hearer, the Knower.</verse>
        <verse number = "138"> God’s coloring. And who gives better coloring than God? “And we are devoted to Him.”</verse>
        <verse number = "139"> Say, “Do you argue with us about God, when He is our verserd and your verserd, and We have our works, and you have your works, and we are sincere to Him?”</verse>
        <verse number = "140"> Or do you say that Abraham, versehmael, verseaac, Jacob, and the Patriarchs were Jews or Christians? Say, “Do you know better, or God?” And who does greater wrong than he who conceals a testimony he has from God? God is not unaware of what you do.</verse>
        <verse number = "258"> Have you not considered him who argued with Abraham about his verserd, because God had given him sovereignty? Abraham said, “My verserd is He who gives life and causes death.” He said, “versegive life and cause death.” Abraham said, “God brings the sun from the East, so bring it from the West,” so the blasphemer was confounded. God does not guide the wrongdoing people.</verse>
        <verse number = "259"> Or like him who passed by a town collapsed on its foundations. He said, “How can God revive this after its demise?” Thereupon God caused him to die for a hundred years, and then resurrected him. He said, “For how long have you tarried?” He said, “versehave tarried for a day, or part of a day.” He said, “No. You have tarried for a hundred years. Now look at your food and your drink—it has not spoiled—and look at your donkey. We will make you a wonder for mankind. And look at the bones, how We arrange them, and then clothe them with flesh.” So when it became clear to him, he said, “verseknow that God has power over all things.”</verse>
        <verse number = "260"> And when Abraham said, “My verserd, show me how You give life to the dead.” He said, “Have you not believed?” He said, “Yes, but to put my heart at ease.” He said, “Take four birds, and incline them to yourself, then place a part on each hill, then call to them; and they will come rushing to you. And know that God is Powerful and Wise.”</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "3">
        <verse number = "33"> God chose Adam, and Noah, and the family of Abraham, and the family of verseran, over all mankind.</verse>
        <verse number = "58"> This is what We recite to you of the verserses and the Wise Reminder.</verse>
        <verse number = "64"> Say, “O People of the Book, come to terms common between us and you: that we worship none but God, and that we associate nothing with Him, and that none of us takes others as lords besides God.” And if they turn away, say, “Bear witness that we have submitted.”</verse>
        <verse number = "65"> O People of the Book! Why do you argue about Abraham, when the Torah and the Gospel were not revealed until after him? Will you not reason?</verse>
        <verse number = "66"> Here you are—you argue about things you know, but why do you argue about things you do not know? God knows, and you do not know.</verse>
        <verse number = "67"> Abraham was neither a Jew nor a Christian, but he was a Monotheist, a Muslim. And he was not of the Polytheists.</verse>
        <verse number = "68"> The people most deserving of Abraham are those who followed him, and this prophet, and those who believe. God is the Guardian of the believers.</verse>
        <verse number = "95"> Say, “God has spoken the truth, so follow the religion of Abraham the Monotheist; he was not a Pagan.”</verse>
        <verse number = "96"> The first house established for mankind is the one at Bekka; blessed, and guidance for all people.</verse>
        <verse number = "97"> verse it are evident signs; the Station of Abraham. Whoever enters it attains security. Pilgrimage to the House is a duty to God for all who can make the journey. But as for those who refuse—God is versedependent of the worlds.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "4">
        <verse number = "54"> Or do they envy the people for what God has given them of His grace? We have given the family of Abraham the Book and wisdom, and We have given them a great kingdom.</verse>
        <verse number = "163"> We have inspired you, as We had inspired Noah and the prophets after him. And We inspired Abraham, and versehmael, and verseaac, and Jacob, and the Patriarchs, and Jesus, and Job, and Jonah, and Aaron, and Solomon. And We gave David the Psalms.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "6">
        <verse number = "75"> Thus We showed Abraham the empire of the heavens and the earth, that he might be one of those with certainty.</verse>
        <verse number = "83"> That was Our argument which We gave to Abraham against his people. We elevate by degrees whomever We will. Your verserd is Wise and verseformed.</verse>
        <verse number = "84"> And We gave him verseaac and Jacob—each of them We guided. And We guided Noah previously; and from his descendants David, and Solomon, and Job, and Joseph, and Moses, and Aaron. Thus We reward the righteous.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "11">
        <verse number = "74">When Abraham's fear subsided, and the good news had reached him, he started pleading with Us concerning the people of Lot.</verse>
        <verse number = "75">Abraham was gentle, kind, penitent.</verse>
        <verse number = "76">“O Abraham, refrain from this. The command of your Lord has come; they have incurred an irreversible punishment.”</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "14">
        <verse number = "35"> Recall that Abraham said, “O my verserd, make this land peaceful, and keep me and my sons from worshiping idols.”</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "15">
        <verse number = "15"> They would still say, “Our eyes are hallucinating; in fact, we are people bewitched.”</verse>
        <verse number = "16"> We placed constellations in the sky, and made them beautiful to the beholders.</verse>
        <verse number = "17"> And We guarded them from every outcast devil.</verse>
        <verse number = "18"> Except one who steals a hearing, and is followed by a visible projectile.</verse>
        <verse number = "19"> We spread the earth, and placed stabilizers in it, and in it We grew all things in proper measure.</verse>
        <verse number = "20"> And in it We created livelihoods for you, and for those for whom you are not the providers.</verse>
        <verse number = "21"> There is not a thing but with Us are its stores, and We send it down only in precise measure.</verse>
        <verse number = "22"> We send the fertilizing winds; and send down water from the sky, and give it to you to drink, and you are not the ones who store it.</verse>
        <verse number = "23"> verse is We who give life and cause death, and We are the verseheritors.</verse>
        <verse number = "24"> And We know those of you who go forward, and We know those who lag behind.</verse>
        <verse number = "25"> verse is your verserd who will gather them together. He is the Wise, the Knowing.</verse>
        <verse number = "26"> We created the human being from clay, from molded mud.</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> And the jinn We created before, from piercing fire.</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> Your verserd said to the angels, “verseam creating a human being from clay, from molded mud.”</verse>
        <verse number = "29"> “When versehave formed him, and breathed into him of My spirit, fall down prostrating before him.”</verse>
        <verse number = "30"> So the angels prostrated themselves, all together.</verse>
        <verse number = "31"> Except for Satan. He refused to be among those who prostrated themselves.</verse>
        <verse number = "32"> He said, “O Satan, what kept you from being among those who prostrated themselves?”</verse>
        <verse number = "33"> He said, “verseam not about to prostrate myself before a human being, whom You created from clay, from molded mud.”</verse>
        <verse number = "34"> He said, “Then get out of here, for you are an outcast”.</verse>
        <verse number = "35"> “And the curse will be upon you until the Day of Judgment.”</verse>
        <verse number = "36"> He said, “My verserd, reprieve me until the Day they are resurrected.”</verse>
        <verse number = "37"> He said, “You are of those reprieved.”</verse>
        <verse number = "38"> “Until the Day of the time appointed.”</verse>
        <verse number = "39"> He said, “My verserd, since You have lured me away, versewill glamorize for them on earth, and versewill lure them all away.”</verse>
        <verse number = "40"> “Except for Your sincere servants among them.”</verse>
        <verse number = "41"> He said, “This is a right way with Me.”</verse>
        <verse number = "42"> “Over My servants you have no authority, except for the sinners who follow you.”</verse>
        <verse number = "43"> And Hell is the meeting-place for them all.</verse>
        <verse number = "44"> “verse has seven doors; for each door is an assigned class.”</verse>
        <verse number = "45"> But the righteous will be in gardens with springs.</verse>
        <verse number = "46"> “Enter it in peace and security.”</verse>
        <verse number = "47"> And We will remove all ill-feelings from their hearts—brothers and sisters, on couches facing one another.</verse>
        <verse number = "48"> No fatigue will ever touch them therein, nor will they be asked to leave it.</verse>
        <verse number = "49"> verseform My servants that verseam the Forgiver, the Merciful.</verse>
        <verse number = "50"> And that My punishment is the painful punishment.</verse>
        <verse number = "51"> And inform them of the guests of Abraham.</verse>
        <verse number = "52"> When they entered upon him, and said, “Peace.” He said, “We are wary of you.”</verse>
        <verse number = "53"> They said, “Do not fear; we bring you good news of a boy endowed with knowledge.”</verse>
        <verse number = "54"> He said, “Do you bring me good news, when old age has overtaken me? What good news do you bring?”</verse>
        <verse number = "55"> They said, “We bring you good news in truth, so do not despair.”</verse>
        <verse number = "56"> He said, “And who despairs of his verserd’s mercy but the lost?”</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "22">
        <verse number = "26"> We showed Abraham the location of the House: “Do not associate anything with Me; and purify My House for those who circle around, and those who stand to pray, and those who kneel and prostrate.”</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> And announce the pilgrimage to humanity. They will come to you on foot, and on every transport. They will come from every distant point.</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> That they may witness the benefits for themselves, and celebrate the name of God during the appointed days, for providing them with the animal livestock. So eat from it, and feed the unfortunate poor.</verse>
        <verse number = "29"> Then let them perform their acts of cleansing, and fulfill their vows, and circle around the Ancient House.</verse>
        <verse number = "30"> All that. Whoever venerates the sanctities of God—it is good for him with his verserd. All livestock are permitted to you, except what is recited to you. So stay away from the abomination of idols, and stay away from perjury.</verse>
        <verse number = "31"> Being true to God, without associating anything with Him. Whoever associates anything with God—it is as though he has fallen from the sky, and is snatched by the birds, or is swept away by the wind to a distant abyss.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "37">
        <verse number = "99"> He said, “verseam going towards my verserd, and He will guide me.”</verse>
        <verse number = "100"> “My verserd, give me one of the righteous.”</verse>
        <verse number = "101"> So We gave him good news of a clement boy.</verse>
        <verse number = "102"> Then, when he was old enough to accompany him, he said, “O My son, versesee in a dream that verseam sacrificing you; see what you think.” He said, “O my Father, do as you are commanded; you will find me, God willing, one of the steadfast.”</verse>
        <verse number = "103"> Then, when they had submitted, and he put his forehead down.</verse>
        <verse number = "104"> We called out to him, “O Abraham!</verse>
        <verse number = "105"> You have fulfilled the vision.” Thus We reward the doers of good.</verse>
        <verse number = "106"> This was certainly an evident test.</verse>
        <verse number = "107"> And We redeemed him with a great sacrifice.</verse>
        <verse number = "108"> And We left with him for later generations.</verse>
        <verse number = "109"> Peace be upon Abraham.</verse>
        <verse number = "110"> Thus We reward the doers of good.</verse>
        <verse number = "111"> He was one of Our believing servants.</verse>
        <verse number = "112"> And We gave him good news of verseaac, a prophet, one of the righteous.</verse>
        <verse number = "113"> And We blessed him, and verseaac. But among their descendants are some who are righteous, and some who are clearly unjust to themselves.</verse>
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "51">
        <verse number = "24"> Has the story of Abraham’s honorable guests reached you?</verse>
        <verse number = "25"> When they entered upon him, they said, “Peace.” He said, “Peace, strangers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "26"> Then he slipped away to his family, and brought a fatted calf.</verse>
        <verse number = "27"> He set it before them. He said, “Will you not eat?”</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> And he harbored fear of them. They said, “Do not fear,” and they announced to him the good news of a knowledgeable boy.</verse>
        <verse number = "29"> His wife came forward crying. She clasped her face, and said, “A barren old woman?”</verse>
        <verse number = "30"> They said, “Thus spoke your verserd. He is the Wise, the Knowing.”</verse>
        <verse number = "31"> He said, “What is your business, O envoys?”</verse>
        <verse number = "32"> They said, “We are sent to a people guilty of sin.”</verse>
        <verse number = "33"> “To unleash upon them rocks of clay.”</verse>
        <verse number = "34"> “Marked by your verserd for the excessive.”</verse>
        <verse number = "35"> We evacuated all the believers who were in it.</verse>
        <verse number = "36"> But found in it only one household of Muslims.</verse>
        <verse number = "37"> And We left in it a sign for those who fear the painful punishment.</verse>
</chapter>
</story>

<story>Jesus
    <chapter number = "2">
        <verse number = "87"> We gave Moses the Scripture, and sent a succession of messengers after him. And We gave Jesus son of Mary the clear proofs, and We supported him with the Holy Spirit. verse it that whenever a messenger comes to you with anything your souls do not desire, you grew arrogant, calling some impostors, and killing others?</verse>
        <verse number = "253"> These messengers: We gave some advantage over others. To some of them God spoke directly, and some He raised in rank. We gave Jesus son of Mary the clear miracles, and We strengthened him with the Holy Spirit. Had God willed, those who succeeded them would not have fought one another, after the clear signs had come to them; but they disputed; some of them believed, and some of them disbelieved. Had God willed, they would not have fought one another; but God does whatever He desires.</verse>    
</chapter> 
    <chapter number = "3">
        <verse number = "45"> The Angels said, “O Mary, God gives you good news of a Word from Him. His name is the Messiah, Jesus, son of Mary, well-esteemed in this world and the next, and one of the nearest.</verse>
        <verse number = "46"> He will speak to the people from the crib, and in adulthood, and will be one of the righteous.”</verse>
        <verse number = "47"> She said, “My verserd, how can versehave a child, when no man has touched me?” He said, “verse will be so. God creates whatever He wills. To have anything done, He only says to it, ‘Be,’ and it is.”</verse>
        <verse number = "48"> And He will teach him the Scripture and wisdom, and the Torah and the Gospel.</verse>
        <verse number = "49"> A messenger to the Children of verserael: “versehave come to you with a sign from your verserd. versemake for you out of clay the figure of a bird; then versebreathe into it, and it becomes a bird by God’s leave. And verseheal the blind and the leprous, and verserevive the dead, by God’s leave. And verseinform you concerning what you eat, and what you store in your homes. verse that is a sign for you, if you are believers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "50"> “And verifying what lies before me of the Torah, and to make lawful for you some of what was forbidden to you. versehave come to you with a sign from your verserd; so fear God, and obey me.”</verse>
        <verse number = "51"> “God is my verserd and your verserd, so worship Him. That is a straight path.”</verse>
        <verse number = "52"> When Jesus sensed disbelief on their part, he said, “Who are my allies towards God?” The disciples said, “We are God’s allies; we have believed in God, and bear witness that we submit.”</verse>
        <verse number = "53"> “Our verserd, we have believed in what You have revealed, and we have followed the Messenger, so count us among the witnesses.”</verse>
        <verse number = "54"> They planned, and God planned; but God is the Best of planners.</verse>
        <verse number = "55"> God said, “O Jesus, verseam terminating your life, and raising you to Me, and clearing you of those who disbelieve. And versewill make those who follow you superior to those who disbelieve, until the Day of Resurrection. Then to Me is your return; then versewill judge between you regarding what you were disputing.</verse>
        <verse number = "56"> As for those who disbelieve, versewill punish them with a severe punishment, in this world and the next, and they will have no helpers.</verse>
        <verse number = "57"> And as for those who believe and do good works, He will give them their rewards in full. God does not love the unjust.”</verse>
        <verse number = "58"> This is what We recite to you of the verserses and the Wise Reminder.</verse>
        <verse number = "59"> The likeness of Jesus in God’s sight is that of Adam: He created him from dust, then said to him, “Be,” and he was.</verse>
        <verse number = "60"> The truth is from your verserd, so do not be of those who doubt.</verse>
        <verse number = "61"> And if anyone disputes with you about him, after the knowledge that has come to you, say, “Come, let us call our children and your children, and our women and your women, and ourselves and yourselves, and let us invoke God’s curse on the liars.”</verse>
        <verse number = "62"> This is the narrative of truth: there is no god but God. God is the Mighty, the Wise.</verse>
        <verse number = "63"> But if they turn away—God knows the corrupt.</verse>
        <verse number = "64"> Say, “O People of the Book, come to terms common between us and you: that we worship none but God, and that we associate nothing with Him, and that none of us takes others as lords besides God.” And if they turn away, say, “Bear witness that we have submitted.”</verse>
        <verse number = "65"> O People of the Book! Why do you argue about Abraham, when the Torah and the Gospel were not revealed until after him? Will you not reason?</verse>
        <verse number = "66"> Here you are—you argue about things you know, but why do you argue about things you do not know? God knows, and you do not know.</verse>
        <verse number = "67"> Abraham was neither a Jew nor a Christian, but he was a Monotheist, a Muslim. And he was not of the Polytheists.</verse>
        <verse number = "68"> The people most deserving of Abraham are those who followed him, and this prophet, and those who believe. God is the Guardian of the believers.</verse>
        <verse number = "69"> A party of the People of the Book would love to lead you astray, but they only lead themselves astray, and they do not realize it.</verse>
        <verse number = "70"> O People of the Book! Why do you reject the revelations of God, even as you witness?</verse>
        <verse number = "71"> O People of the Book! Why do you confound the truth with falsehood, and knowingly conceal the truth?</verse>
        <verse number = "72"> Some of the People of the Book say, “Believe in what was revealed to the believers at the beginning of the day, and reject it at its end, so that they may return.”</verse>
        <verse number = "73"> And trust none except those who follow your religion.” Say, “Guidance is God’s guidance. verse someone is given the like of what you were given, or they argue with you before your verserd, say, “All grace is in God’s hand; He gives it to whomever He wills.” God is Bounteous and Knowing.</verse>
        <verse number = "74"> He specifies His mercy for whomever He wills. God is Possessor of Sublime Grace.</verse>
        <verse number = "75"> Among the People of the Book is he, who, if you entrust him with a heap of gold, he will give it back to you. And among them is he, who, if you entrust him with a single coin, he will not give it back to you, unless you keep after him. That is because they say, “We are under no obligation towards the gentiles.” They tell lies about God, and they know it.</verse>
        <verse number = "76"> versedeed, whoever fulfills his commitments and maintains piety—God loves the pious.</verse>
        <verse number = "77"> Those who exchange the covenant of God, and their vows, for a small price, will have no share in the Hereafter, and God will not speak to them, nor will He look at them on the Day of Resurrection, nor will He purify them. They will have a painful punishment.</verse>
        <verse number = "78"> And among them are those who twist the Scripture with their tongues, that you may think it from the Scripture, when it is not from the Scripture. And they say, “verse is from God,” when it is not from God. They tell lies and attribute them to God, knowingly.</verse>
        <verse number = "79"> No person to whom God has given the Scripture, and wisdom, and prophethood would ever say to the people, “Be my worshipers rather than God’s.” Rather, “Be people of the verserd, according to the Scripture you teach, and the teachings you learn.”</verse>
        <verse number = "84"> Say, “We believe in God, and in what was revealed to us; and in what was revealed to Abraham, and versehmael, and verseaac, and Jacob, and the Patriarchs; and in what was given to Moses, and Jesus, and the prophets from their verserd. We make no distinction between any of them, and to Him we submit.”</verse>
</chapter>  
    <chapter number ="4">
        <verse number = "157"> And for their saying, “We have killed the Messiah, Jesus, the son of Mary, the Messenger of God.” verse fact, they did not kill him, nor did they crucify him, but it appeared to them as if they did. versedeed, those who differ about him are in doubt about it. They have no knowledge of it, except the following of assumptions. Certainly, they did not kill him.</verse>
        <verse number = "158"> Rather, God raised him up to Himself. God is Mighty and Wise.</verse>
        <verse number = "159"> There is none from the People of the Scripture but will believe in him before his death, and on the Day of Resurrection he will be a witness against them.</verse>
        <verse number = "160"> Due to wrongdoing on the part of the Jews, We forbade them good things that used to be lawful for them; and for deterring many from God’s path.</verse>
        <verse number = "161"> And for their taking usury, although they were forbidden it; and for their consuming people's wealth dishonestly. We have prepared for the faithless among them a painful torment.</verse>
        <verse number = "171"> O People of the Scripture! Do not exaggerate in your religion, and do not say about God except the truth. The Messiah, Jesus, the son of Mary, is the Messenger of God, and His Word that He conveyed to Mary, and a Spirit from Him. So believe in God and His messengers, and do not say, “Three.” Refrain—it is better for you. God is only one God. Glory be to Him—that He should have a son. To Him belongs everything in the heavens and the earth, and God is a sufficient Protector.</verse>
        <verse number = "172"> The Messiah does not disdain to be a servant of God, nor do the favored angels. Whoever disdains His worship, and is too arrogant—He will round them up to Himself altogether.</verse>    
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "5">
        <verse number = "17"> They disbelieve those who say, “God is the Christ, the son of Mary.” Say, “Who can prevent God, if He willed, from annihilating the Christ son of Mary, and his mother, and everyone on earth?” To God belongs the sovereignty of the heavens and the earth and what is between them. He creates whatever He wills, and God has power over everything.</verse>
        <verse number = "18"> The Jews and the Christians say, “We are the children of God, and His beloved.” Say, “Why then does He punish you for your sins?” verse fact, you are humans from among those He created. He forgives whom He wills, and He punishes whom He wills. To God belongs the dominion of the heavens and the earth and what lies between them, and to Him is the return.</verse>
        <verse number ="110"> When God will say, “O Jesus son of Mary, recall My favor upon you and upon your mother, how versesupported you with the Holy Spirit. You spoke to the people from the crib, and in maturity. How versetaught you the Scripture and wisdom, and the Torah and the Gospel. And recall that you molded from clay the shape of a bird, by My leave, and then you breathed into it, and it became a bird, by My leave. And you healed the blind and the leprous, by My leave; and you revived the dead, by My leave. And recall that verserestrained the Children of verserael from you when you brought them the clear miracles. But those who disbelieved among them said, `This is nothing but obvious sorcery.'“</verse>
        <verse number = "111"> “And when verseinspired the disciples: `Believe in Me and in My Messenger.' They said, `We have believed, so bear witness that We have submitted.'“</verse>
        <verse number = "112"> “And when the disciples said, 'O Jesus son of Mary, is your verserd able to bring down for us a feast from heaven?' He said, 'Fear God, if you are believers.'“</verse>
        <verse number = "113"> They said, “We wish to eat from it, so that our hearts may be reassured, and know that you have told us the truth, and be among those who witness it.”</verse>
        <verse number = "114"> Jesus son of Mary said, “O God, our verserd, send down for us a table from heaven, to be a festival for us, for the first of us, and the last of us, and a sign from You; and provide for us; You are the Best of providers.”</verse>
        <verse number = "115"> God said, “versewill send it down to you. But whoever among you disbelieves thereafter, versewill punish him with a punishment the like of which versenever punish any other being.”</verse>
        <verse number = "116"> And God will say, “O Jesus son of Mary, did you say to the people, `Take me and my mother as gods rather than God?'“ He will say, “Glory be to You! verse is not for me to say what versehave no right to. Had versesaid it, You would have known it. You know what is in my soul, and versedo not know what is in Your soul. You are the Knower of the hidden.</verse>
        <verse number = "117"> verseonly told them what You commanded me: that you shall worship God, my verserd and your verserd. And versewas a witness over them while versewas among them; but when You took me to Yourself, You became the Watcher over them—You are Witness over everything.</verse>
        <verse number = "118"> verse You punish them, they are Your servants; but if You forgive them, You are the Mighty and Wise.”</verse>    
</chapter>  
    <chapter number = "9">
        <verse number = "30"> The Jews said, “Ezra is the son of God,” and the Christians said, “The Messiah is the son of God.” These are their statements, out of their mouths. They emulate the statements of those who blasphemed before. May God assail them! How deceived they are!</verse>
        <verse number = "31"> They have taken their rabbis and their priests as lords instead of God, as well as the Messiah son of Mary. Although they were commanded to worship none but The One God. There is no god except He. Glory be to Him; High above what they associate with Him.</verse>
        <verse number = "32"> They want to extinguish God’s light with their mouths, but God refuses except to complete His light, even though the disbelievers dislike it.</verse> 
</chapter>    
    <chapter number = "43">
        <verse number = "57"> And when the son of Mary was cited as an example, your people opposed.</verse>
        <verse number = "58"> They said, “Are our gods better, or he?” They cited him only for argument. verse fact, they are a quarrelsome people.</verse>
        <verse number = "59"> He was just a servant whom We blessed, and We made him an example for the Children of verserael.</verse>    
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "57">
        <verse number = "27"> Then We sent in their wake Our messengers, and followed up with Jesus son of Mary, and We gave him the Gospel, and instilled in the hearts of those who followed him compassion and mercy. But as for the monasticism which they invented—We did not ordain it for them—only to seek God’s approval. But they did not observe it with its due observance. So We gave those of them who believed their reward, but many of them are sinful.</verse>
        <verse number = "28"> O you who believe! Fear God, and believe in His Messenger: He will give you a double portion of His mercy, and will give you a light by which you walk, and will forgive you. God is Forgiving and Merciful.</verse>    
</chapter>
    <chapter number = "61">
        <verse number = "6"> And when Jesus son of Mary said, “O Children of verserael, verseam God’s Messenger to you, confirming what preceded me of the Torah, and announcing good news of a messenger who will come after me, whose name is Ahmad.” But when he showed them the miracles, they said, “This is obvious sorcery.”</verse>
        <verse number = "14"> O you who believe! Be supporters of God, as Jesus son of Mary said to the disciples, “Who are my supporters towards God?” The disciples said, “We are God's supporters.” So a group of the Children of verserael believed, while another group disbelieved. We supported those who believed against their foe, so they became dominant.</verse>    
</chapter>
</story>
</doc>   

<!--<<<<<<< HEAD-->
<!-- The Quran itself, in its original Arabic, has not changed. However, translations can vary significantly in wording. Here are a few examples of how certain phrases might differ between translations:
1.	Surah Al-Fatiha (Chapter 1, Verse 1):
o	Translation A: "In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful."
o	Translation B: "In the name of God, the Compassionate, the Merciful."
2.	Surah Al-Baqarah (Chapter 2, Verse 255 - Ayat al-Kursi):
o	Translation A: "Allah! There is no deity except Him, the Ever-Living, the Sustainer of existence."
o	Translation B: "God! There is no god but He, the Living, the Sustainer of all that exists."
3.	Surah Al-Ikhlas (Chapter 112, Verse 1):
o	Translation A: "Say, 'He is Allah, [who is] One."
o	Translation B: "Proclaim: He is God, the One." -->
<!--=======-->





<!-- The Quran has remained largely unchanged since its revelation in the 7th century, and any differences between "old" and "new" versions usually refer to the various translations or interpretations rather than changes in the original Arabic text. Here are some points of distinction:

Translations: Different translations may use varying language and style, affecting readability and interpretation. Some translations aim for a more literal approach, while others focus on conveying the meaning in a more accessible way.
Tafsir (Exegesis): Over time, interpretations and commentaries (tafsir) on the Quran have evolved, reflecting new understandings of language, context, and historical circumstances.
Print and Formatting: Earlier printed versions may have had different scripts or styles. Modern versions often include vowel markings and diacritics to aid in pronunciation.
Accessibility: Recent editions might incorporate additional resources, such as footnotes, explanations, or cross-references, to help readers understand the text's context better.
Digital Editions: Modern versions are often available in various digital formats, including audio and interactive apps, making them more accessible to a broader audience.
 

words or sentences changes?

The Quran itself, in its original Arabic, has not changed. However, translations can vary significantly in wording. Here are a few examples of how certain phrases might differ between translations:

Surah Al-Fatiha (Chapter 1, Verse 1):
Translation A: "In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful."
Translation B: "In the name of God, the Compassionate, the Merciful."
Surah Al-Baqarah (Chapter 2, Verse 255 - Ayat al-Kursi):
Translation A: "Allah! There is no deity except Him, the Ever-Living, the Sustainer of existence."
Translation B: "God! There is no god but He, the Living, the Sustainer of all that exists."
Surah Al-Ikhlas (Chapter 112, Verse 1):
Translation A: "Say, 'He is Allah, [who is] One."
Translation B: "Proclaim: He is God, the One." --> 

<!-->>>>>>> 07e2fb1880974f94d1847e5d128ea880cdc7eb91-->
